(function(){const t=document.createElement("link").relList;if(t&&t.supports&&t.supports("modulepreload"))return;for(const a of document.querySelectorAll('link[rel="modulepreload"]'))c(a);new MutationObserver(a=>{for(const i of a)if(i.type==="childList")for(const r of i.addedNodes)r.tagName==="LINK"&&r.rel==="modulepreload"&&c(r)}).observe(document,{childList:!0,subtree:!0});function n(a){const i={};return a.integrity&&(i.integrity=a.integrity),a.referrerPolicy&&(i.referrerPolicy=a.referrerPolicy),a.crossOrigin==="use-credentials"?i.credentials="include":a.crossOrigin==="anonymous"?i.credentials="omit":i.credentials="same-origin",i}function c(a){if(a.ep)return;a.ep=!0;const i=n(a);fetch(a.href,i)}})();/**
* @vue/shared v3.4.35
* (c) 2018-present Yuxi (Evan) You and Vue contributors
* @license MIT
**//*! #__NO_SIDE_EFFECTS__ */function Cn(e,t){const n=new Set(e.split(","));return c=>n.has(c)}const U={},et=[],he=()=>{},ci=()=>!1,Dt=e=>e.charCodeAt(0)===111&&e.charCodeAt(1)===110&&(e.charCodeAt(2)>122||e.charCodeAt(2)<97),Sn=e=>e.startsWith("onUpdate:"),ae=Object.assign,Pn=(e,t)=>{const n=e.indexOf(t);n>-1&&e.splice(n,1)},ai=Object.prototype.hasOwnProperty,O=(e,t)=>ai.call(e,t),w=Array.isArray,tt=e=>Bt(e)==="[object Map]",Fc=e=>Bt(e)==="[object Set]",x=e=>typeof e=="function",te=e=>typeof e=="string",Re=e=>typeof e=="symbol",z=e=>e!==null&&typeof e=="object",Lc=e=>(z(e)||x(e))&&x(e.then)&&x(e.catch),qc=Object.prototype.toString,Bt=e=>qc.call(e),ii=e=>Bt(e).slice(8,-1),$c=e=>Bt(e)==="[object Object]",En=e=>te(e)&&e!=="NaN"&&e[0]!=="-"&&""+parseInt(e,10)===e,ut=Cn(",key,ref,ref_for,ref_key,onVnodeBeforeMount,onVnodeMounted,onVnodeBeforeUpdate,onVnodeUpdated,onVnodeBeforeUnmount,onVnodeUnmounted"),Kt=e=>{const t=Object.create(null);return n=>t[n]||(t[n]=e(n))},ri=/-(\w)/g,Ge=Kt(e=>e.replace(ri,(t,n)=>n?n.toUpperCase():"")),oi=/\B([A-Z])/g,Je=Kt(e=>e.replace(oi,"-$1").toLowerCase()),Hc=Kt(e=>e.charAt(0).toUpperCase()+e.slice(1)),an=Kt(e=>e?`on${Hc(e)}`:""),Te=(e,t)=>!Object.is(e,t),rn=(e,...t)=>{for(let n=0;n<e.length;n++)e[n](...t)},Dc=(e,t,n,c=!1)=>{Object.defineProperty(e,t,{configurable:!0,enumerable:!1,writable:c,value:n})},si=e=>{const t=parseFloat(e);return isNaN(t)?e:t};let cc;const Bc=()=>cc||(cc=typeof globalThis<"u"?globalThis:typeof self<"u"?self:typeof window<"u"?window:typeof global<"u"?global:{});function On(e){if(w(e)){const t={};for(let n=0;n<e.length;n++){const c=e[n],a=te(c)?bi(c):On(c);if(a)for(const i in a)t[i]=a[i]}return t}else if(te(e)||z(e))return e}const di=/;(?![^(]*\))/g,fi=/:([^]+)/,li=/\/\*[^]*?\*\//g;function bi(e){const t={};return e.replace(li,"").split(di).forEach(n=>{if(n){const c=n.split(fi);c.length>1&&(t[c[0].trim()]=c[1].trim())}}),t}function Ut(e){let t="";if(te(e))t=e;else if(w(e))for(let n=0;n<e.length;n++){const c=Ut(e[n]);c&&(t+=c+" ")}else if(z(e))for(const n in e)e[n]&&(t+=n+" ");return t.trim()}const ui="itemscope,allowfullscreen,formnovalidate,ismap,nomodule,novalidate,readonly",pi=Cn(ui);function Kc(e){return!!e||e===""}const Uc=e=>!!(e&&e.__v_isRef===!0),Ot=e=>te(e)?e:e==null?"":w(e)||z(e)&&(e.toString===qc||!x(e.toString))?Uc(e)?Ot(e.value):JSON.stringify(e,zc,2):String(e),zc=(e,t)=>Uc(t)?zc(e,t.value):tt(t)?{[`Map(${t.size})`]:[...t.entries()].reduce((n,[c,a],i)=>(n[on(c,i)+" =>"]=a,n),{})}:Fc(t)?{[`Set(${t.size})`]:[...t.values()].map(n=>on(n))}:Re(t)?on(t):z(t)&&!w(t)&&!$c(t)?String(t):t,on=(e,t="")=>{var n;return Re(e)?`Symbol(${(n=e.description)!=null?n:t})`:e};/**
* @vue/reactivity v3.4.35
* (c) 2018-present Yuxi (Evan) You and Vue contributors
* @license MIT
**/let le;class Wc{constructor(t=!1){this.detached=t,this._active=!0,this.effects=[],this.cleanups=[],this.parent=le,!t&&le&&(this.index=(le.scopes||(le.scopes=[])).push(this)-1)}get active(){return this._active}run(t){if(this._active){const n=le;try{return le=this,t()}finally{le=n}}}on(){le=this}off(){le=this.parent}stop(t){if(this._active){let n,c;for(n=0,c=this.effects.length;n<c;n++)this.effects[n].stop();for(n=0,c=this.cleanups.length;n<c;n++)this.cleanups[n]();if(this.scopes)for(n=0,c=this.scopes.length;n<c;n++)this.scopes[n].stop(!0);if(!this.detached&&this.parent&&!t){const a=this.parent.scopes.pop();a&&a!==this&&(this.parent.scopes[this.index]=a,a.index=this.index)}this.parent=void 0,this._active=!1}}}function Gc(e){return new Wc(e)}function hi(e,t=le){t&&t.active&&t.effects.push(e)}function Zc(){return le}function mi(e){le&&le.cleanups.push(e)}let Ue;class Tn{constructor(t,n,c,a){this.fn=t,this.trigger=n,this.scheduler=c,this.active=!0,this.deps=[],this._dirtyLevel=4,this._trackId=0,this._runnings=0,this._shouldSchedule=!1,this._depsLength=0,hi(this,a)}get dirty(){if(this._dirtyLevel===2||this._dirtyLevel===3){this._dirtyLevel=1,Fe();for(let t=0;t<this._depsLength;t++){const n=this.deps[t];if(n.computed&&(Ii(n.computed),this._dirtyLevel>=4))break}this._dirtyLevel===1&&(this._dirtyLevel=0),Le()}return this._dirtyLevel>=4}set dirty(t){this._dirtyLevel=t?4:0}run(){if(this._dirtyLevel=0,!this.active)return this.fn();let t=Ee,n=Ue;try{return Ee=!0,Ue=this,this._runnings++,ac(this),this.fn()}finally{ic(this),this._runnings--,Ue=n,Ee=t}}stop(){this.active&&(ac(this),ic(this),this.onStop&&this.onStop(),this.active=!1)}}function Ii(e){return e.value}function ac(e){e._trackId++,e._depsLength=0}function ic(e){if(e.deps.length>e._depsLength){for(let t=e._depsLength;t<e.deps.length;t++)Jc(e.deps[t],e);e.deps.length=e._depsLength}}function Jc(e,t){const n=e.get(t);n!==void 0&&t._trackId!==n&&(e.delete(t),e.size===0&&e.cleanup())}let Ee=!0,mn=0;const Yc=[];function Fe(){Yc.push(Ee),Ee=!1}function Le(){const e=Yc.pop();Ee=e===void 0?!0:e}function Mn(){mn++}function Rn(){for(mn--;!mn&&In.length;)In.shift()()}function Qc(e,t,n){if(t.get(e)!==e._trackId){t.set(e,e._trackId);const c=e.deps[e._depsLength];c!==t?(c&&Jc(c,e),e.deps[e._depsLength++]=t):e._depsLength++}}const In=[];function ea(e,t,n){Mn();for(const c of e.keys()){let a;c._dirtyLevel<t&&(a??(a=e.get(c)===c._trackId))&&(c._shouldSchedule||(c._shouldSchedule=c._dirtyLevel===0),c._dirtyLevel=t),c._shouldSchedule&&(a??(a=e.get(c)===c._trackId))&&(c.trigger(),(!c._runnings||c.allowRecurse)&&c._dirtyLevel!==2&&(c._shouldSchedule=!1,c.scheduler&&In.push(c.scheduler)))}Rn()}const ta=(e,t)=>{const n=new Map;return n.cleanup=e,n.computed=t,n},Lt=new WeakMap,ze=Symbol(""),gn=Symbol("");function de(e,t,n){if(Ee&&Ue){let c=Lt.get(e);c||Lt.set(e,c=new Map);let a=c.get(n);a||c.set(n,a=ta(()=>c.delete(n))),Qc(Ue,a)}}function we(e,t,n,c,a,i){const r=Lt.get(e);if(!r)return;let s=[];if(t==="clear")s=[...r.values()];else if(n==="length"&&w(e)){const f=Number(c);r.forEach((b,l)=>{(l==="length"||!Re(l)&&l>=f)&&s.push(b)})}else switch(n!==void 0&&s.push(r.get(n)),t){case"add":w(e)?En(n)&&s.push(r.get("length")):(s.push(r.get(ze)),tt(e)&&s.push(r.get(gn)));break;case"delete":w(e)||(s.push(r.get(ze)),tt(e)&&s.push(r.get(gn)));break;case"set":tt(e)&&s.push(r.get(ze));break}Mn();for(const f of s)f&&ea(f,4);Rn()}function gi(e,t){const n=Lt.get(e);return n&&n.get(t)}const ki=Cn("__proto__,__v_isRef,__isVue"),na=new Set(Object.getOwnPropertyNames(Symbol).filter(e=>e!=="arguments"&&e!=="caller").map(e=>Symbol[e]).filter(Re)),rc=vi();function vi(){const e={};return["includes","indexOf","lastIndexOf"].forEach(t=>{e[t]=function(...n){const c=R(this);for(let i=0,r=this.length;i<r;i++)de(c,"get",i+"");const a=c[t](...n);return a===-1||a===!1?c[t](...n.map(R)):a}}),["push","pop","shift","unshift","splice"].forEach(t=>{e[t]=function(...n){Fe(),Mn();const c=R(this)[t].apply(this,n);return Rn(),Le(),c}}),e}function Vi(e){Re(e)||(e=String(e));const t=R(this);return de(t,"has",e),t.hasOwnProperty(e)}class ca{constructor(t=!1,n=!1){this._isReadonly=t,this._isShallow=n}get(t,n,c){const a=this._isReadonly,i=this._isShallow;if(n==="__v_isReactive")return!a;if(n==="__v_isReadonly")return a;if(n==="__v_isShallow")return i;if(n==="__v_raw")return c===(a?i?Oi:oa:i?ra:ia).get(t)||Object.getPrototypeOf(t)===Object.getPrototypeOf(c)?t:void 0;const r=w(t);if(!a){if(r&&O(rc,n))return Reflect.get(rc,n,c);if(n==="hasOwnProperty")return Vi}const s=Reflect.get(t,n,c);return(Re(n)?na.has(n):ki(n))||(a||de(t,"get",n),i)?s:Q(s)?r&&En(n)?s:s.value:z(s)?a?sa(s):Wt(s):s}}class aa extends ca{constructor(t=!1){super(!1,t)}set(t,n,c,a){let i=t[n];if(!this._isShallow){const f=Ze(i);if(!it(c)&&!Ze(c)&&(i=R(i),c=R(c)),!w(t)&&Q(i)&&!Q(c))return f?!1:(i.value=c,!0)}const r=w(t)&&En(n)?Number(n)<t.length:O(t,n),s=Reflect.set(t,n,c,a);return t===R(a)&&(r?Te(c,i)&&we(t,"set",n,c):we(t,"add",n,c)),s}deleteProperty(t,n){const c=O(t,n);t[n];const a=Reflect.deleteProperty(t,n);return a&&c&&we(t,"delete",n,void 0),a}has(t,n){const c=Reflect.has(t,n);return(!Re(n)||!na.has(n))&&de(t,"has",n),c}ownKeys(t){return de(t,"iterate",w(t)?"length":ze),Reflect.ownKeys(t)}}class _i extends ca{constructor(t=!1){super(!0,t)}set(t,n){return!0}deleteProperty(t,n){return!0}}const yi=new aa,Xi=new _i,ji=new aa(!0);const Fn=e=>e,zt=e=>Reflect.getPrototypeOf(e);function At(e,t,n=!1,c=!1){e=e.__v_raw;const a=R(e),i=R(t);n||(Te(t,i)&&de(a,"get",t),de(a,"get",i));const{has:r}=zt(a),s=c?Fn:n?Hn:kt;if(r.call(a,t))return s(e.get(t));if(r.call(a,i))return s(e.get(i));e!==a&&e.get(t)}function xt(e,t=!1){const n=this.__v_raw,c=R(n),a=R(e);return t||(Te(e,a)&&de(c,"has",e),de(c,"has",a)),e===a?n.has(e):n.has(e)||n.has(a)}function Ct(e,t=!1){return e=e.__v_raw,!t&&de(R(e),"iterate",ze),Reflect.get(e,"size",e)}function oc(e,t=!1){!t&&!it(e)&&!Ze(e)&&(e=R(e));const n=R(this);return zt(n).has.call(n,e)||(n.add(e),we(n,"add",e,e)),this}function sc(e,t,n=!1){!n&&!it(t)&&!Ze(t)&&(t=R(t));const c=R(this),{has:a,get:i}=zt(c);let r=a.call(c,e);r||(e=R(e),r=a.call(c,e));const s=i.call(c,e);return c.set(e,t),r?Te(t,s)&&we(c,"set",e,t):we(c,"add",e,t),this}function dc(e){const t=R(this),{has:n,get:c}=zt(t);let a=n.call(t,e);a||(e=R(e),a=n.call(t,e)),c&&c.call(t,e);const i=t.delete(e);return a&&we(t,"delete",e,void 0),i}function fc(){const e=R(this),t=e.size!==0,n=e.clear();return t&&we(e,"clear",void 0,void 0),n}function St(e,t){return function(c,a){const i=this,r=i.__v_raw,s=R(r),f=t?Fn:e?Hn:kt;return!e&&de(s,"iterate",ze),r.forEach((b,l)=>c.call(a,f(b),f(l),i))}}function Pt(e,t,n){return function(...c){const a=this.__v_raw,i=R(a),r=tt(i),s=e==="entries"||e===Symbol.iterator&&r,f=e==="keys"&&r,b=a[e](...c),l=n?Fn:t?Hn:kt;return!t&&de(i,"iterate",f?gn:ze),{next(){const{value:g,done:y}=b.next();return y?{value:g,done:y}:{value:s?[l(g[0]),l(g[1])]:l(g),done:y}},[Symbol.iterator](){return this}}}}function xe(e){return function(...t){return e==="delete"?!1:e==="clear"?void 0:this}}function wi(){const e={get(i){return At(this,i)},get size(){return Ct(this)},has:xt,add:oc,set:sc,delete:dc,clear:fc,forEach:St(!1,!1)},t={get(i){return At(this,i,!1,!0)},get size(){return Ct(this)},has:xt,add(i){return oc.call(this,i,!0)},set(i,r){return sc.call(this,i,r,!0)},delete:dc,clear:fc,forEach:St(!1,!0)},n={get(i){return At(this,i,!0)},get size(){return Ct(this,!0)},has(i){return xt.call(this,i,!0)},add:xe("add"),set:xe("set"),delete:xe("delete"),clear:xe("clear"),forEach:St(!0,!1)},c={get(i){return At(this,i,!0,!0)},get size(){return Ct(this,!0)},has(i){return xt.call(this,i,!0)},add:xe("add"),set:xe("set"),delete:xe("delete"),clear:xe("clear"),forEach:St(!0,!0)};return["keys","values","entries",Symbol.iterator].forEach(i=>{e[i]=Pt(i,!1,!1),n[i]=Pt(i,!0,!1),t[i]=Pt(i,!1,!0),c[i]=Pt(i,!0,!0)}),[e,n,t,c]}const[Ni,Ai,xi,Ci]=wi();function Ln(e,t){const n=t?e?Ci:xi:e?Ai:Ni;return(c,a,i)=>a==="__v_isReactive"?!e:a==="__v_isReadonly"?e:a==="__v_raw"?c:Reflect.get(O(n,a)&&a in c?n:c,a,i)}const Si={get:Ln(!1,!1)},Pi={get:Ln(!1,!0)},Ei={get:Ln(!0,!1)};const ia=new WeakMap,ra=new WeakMap,oa=new WeakMap,Oi=new WeakMap;function Ti(e){switch(e){case"Object":case"Array":return 1;case"Map":case"Set":case"WeakMap":case"WeakSet":return 2;default:return 0}}function Mi(e){return e.__v_skip||!Object.isExtensible(e)?0:Ti(ii(e))}function Wt(e){return Ze(e)?e:qn(e,!1,yi,Si,ia)}function Ri(e){return qn(e,!1,ji,Pi,ra)}function sa(e){return qn(e,!0,Xi,Ei,oa)}function qn(e,t,n,c,a){if(!z(e)||e.__v_raw&&!(t&&e.__v_isReactive))return e;const i=a.get(e);if(i)return i;const r=Mi(e);if(r===0)return e;const s=new Proxy(e,r===2?c:n);return a.set(e,s),s}function We(e){return Ze(e)?We(e.__v_raw):!!(e&&e.__v_isReactive)}function Ze(e){return!!(e&&e.__v_isReadonly)}function it(e){return!!(e&&e.__v_isShallow)}function da(e){return e?!!e.__v_raw:!1}function R(e){const t=e&&e.__v_raw;return t?R(t):e}function $n(e){return Object.isExtensible(e)&&Dc(e,"__v_skip",!0),e}const kt=e=>z(e)?Wt(e):e,Hn=e=>z(e)?sa(e):e;class fa{constructor(t,n,c,a){this.getter=t,this._setter=n,this.dep=void 0,this.__v_isRef=!0,this.__v_isReadonly=!1,this.effect=new Tn(()=>t(this._value),()=>Tt(this,this.effect._dirtyLevel===2?2:3)),this.effect.computed=this,this.effect.active=this._cacheable=!a,this.__v_isReadonly=c}get value(){const t=R(this);return(!t._cacheable||t.effect.dirty)&&Te(t._value,t._value=t.effect.run())&&Tt(t,4),la(t),t.effect._dirtyLevel>=2&&Tt(t,2),t._value}set value(t){this._setter(t)}get _dirty(){return this.effect.dirty}set _dirty(t){this.effect.dirty=t}}function Fi(e,t,n=!1){let c,a;const i=x(e);return i?(c=e,a=he):(c=e.get,a=e.set),new fa(c,a,i||!a,n)}function la(e){var t;Ee&&Ue&&(e=R(e),Qc(Ue,(t=e.dep)!=null?t:e.dep=ta(()=>e.dep=void 0,e instanceof fa?e:void 0)))}function Tt(e,t=4,n,c){e=R(e);const a=e.dep;a&&ea(a,t)}function Q(e){return!!(e&&e.__v_isRef===!0)}function nt(e){return Li(e,!1)}function Li(e,t){return Q(e)?e:new qi(e,t)}class qi{constructor(t,n){this.__v_isShallow=n,this.dep=void 0,this.__v_isRef=!0,this._rawValue=n?t:R(t),this._value=n?t:kt(t)}get value(){return la(this),this._value}set value(t){const n=this.__v_isShallow||it(t)||Ze(t);t=n?t:R(t),Te(t,this._rawValue)&&(this._rawValue,this._rawValue=t,this._value=n?t:kt(t),Tt(this,4))}}function ba(e){return Q(e)?e.value:e}const $i={get:(e,t,n)=>ba(Reflect.get(e,t,n)),set:(e,t,n,c)=>{const a=e[t];return Q(a)&&!Q(n)?(a.value=n,!0):Reflect.set(e,t,n,c)}};function ua(e){return We(e)?e:new Proxy(e,$i)}function Hi(e){const t=w(e)?new Array(e.length):{};for(const n in e)t[n]=Bi(e,n);return t}class Di{constructor(t,n,c){this._object=t,this._key=n,this._defaultValue=c,this.__v_isRef=!0}get value(){const t=this._object[this._key];return t===void 0?this._defaultValue:t}set value(t){this._object[this._key]=t}get dep(){return gi(R(this._object),this._key)}}function Bi(e,t,n){const c=e[t];return Q(c)?c:new Di(e,t,n)}/**
* @vue/runtime-core v3.4.35
* (c) 2018-present Yuxi (Evan) You and Vue contributors
* @license MIT
**/function Oe(e,t,n,c){try{return c?e(...c):e()}catch(a){Gt(a,t,n)}}function Ie(e,t,n,c){if(x(e)){const a=Oe(e,t,n,c);return a&&Lc(a)&&a.catch(i=>{Gt(i,t,n)}),a}if(w(e)){const a=[];for(let i=0;i<e.length;i++)a.push(Ie(e[i],t,n,c));return a}}function Gt(e,t,n,c=!0){const a=t?t.vnode:null;if(t){let i=t.parent;const r=t.proxy,s=`https://vuejs.org/error-reference/#runtime-${n}`;for(;i;){const b=i.ec;if(b){for(let l=0;l<b.length;l++)if(b[l](e,r,s)===!1)return}i=i.parent}const f=t.appContext.config.errorHandler;if(f){Fe(),Oe(f,null,10,[e,r,s]),Le();return}}Ki(e,n,a,c)}function Ki(e,t,n,c=!0){console.error(e)}let vt=!1,kn=!1;const ne=[];let Xe=0;const ct=[];let Se=null,Be=0;const pa=Promise.resolve();let Dn=null;function ha(e){const t=Dn||pa;return e?t.then(this?e.bind(this):e):t}function Ui(e){let t=Xe+1,n=ne.length;for(;t<n;){const c=t+n>>>1,a=ne[c],i=Vt(a);i<e||i===e&&a.pre?t=c+1:n=c}return t}function Bn(e){(!ne.length||!ne.includes(e,vt&&e.allowRecurse?Xe+1:Xe))&&(e.id==null?ne.push(e):ne.splice(Ui(e.id),0,e),ma())}function ma(){!vt&&!kn&&(kn=!0,Dn=pa.then(ga))}function zi(e){const t=ne.indexOf(e);t>Xe&&ne.splice(t,1)}function Wi(e){w(e)?ct.push(...e):(!Se||!Se.includes(e,e.allowRecurse?Be+1:Be))&&ct.push(e),ma()}function lc(e,t,n=vt?Xe+1:0){for(;n<ne.length;n++){const c=ne[n];if(c&&c.pre){if(e&&c.id!==e.uid)continue;ne.splice(n,1),n--,c()}}}function Ia(e){if(ct.length){const t=[...new Set(ct)].sort((n,c)=>Vt(n)-Vt(c));if(ct.length=0,Se){Se.push(...t);return}for(Se=t,Be=0;Be<Se.length;Be++){const n=Se[Be];n.active!==!1&&n()}Se=null,Be=0}}const Vt=e=>e.id==null?1/0:e.id,Gi=(e,t)=>{const n=Vt(e)-Vt(t);if(n===0){if(e.pre&&!t.pre)return-1;if(t.pre&&!e.pre)return 1}return n};function ga(e){kn=!1,vt=!0,ne.sort(Gi);try{for(Xe=0;Xe<ne.length;Xe++){const t=ne[Xe];t&&t.active!==!1&&Oe(t,t.i,t.i?15:14)}}finally{Xe=0,ne.length=0,Ia(),vt=!1,Dn=null,(ne.length||ct.length)&&ga()}}let oe=null,Zt=null;function qt(e){const t=oe;return oe=e,Zt=e&&e.type.__scopeId||null,t}function Zi(e){Zt=e}function Ji(){Zt=null}function vn(e,t=oe,n){if(!t||e._n)return e;const c=(...a)=>{c._d&&vc(-1);const i=qt(t);let r;try{r=e(...a)}finally{qt(i),c._d&&vc(1)}return r};return c._n=!0,c._c=!0,c._d=!0,c}function He(e,t,n,c){const a=e.dirs,i=t&&t.dirs;for(let r=0;r<a.length;r++){const s=a[r];i&&(s.oldValue=i[r].value);let f=s.dir[c];f&&(Fe(),Ie(f,n,8,[e.el,s,e,t]),Le())}}function ka(e,t){e.shapeFlag&6&&e.component?ka(e.component.subTree,t):e.shapeFlag&128?(e.ssContent.transition=t.clone(e.ssContent),e.ssFallback.transition=t.clone(e.ssFallback)):e.transition=t}/*! #__NO_SIDE_EFFECTS__ */function va(e,t){return x(e)?ae({name:e.name},t,{setup:e}):e}const pt=e=>!!e.type.__asyncLoader,Va=e=>e.type.__isKeepAlive;function Yi(e,t){_a(e,"a",t)}function Qi(e,t){_a(e,"da",t)}function _a(e,t,n=ce){const c=e.__wdc||(e.__wdc=()=>{let a=n;for(;a;){if(a.isDeactivated)return;a=a.parent}return e()});if(Jt(t,c,n),n){let a=n.parent;for(;a&&a.parent;)Va(a.parent.vnode)&&er(c,t,n,a),a=a.parent}}function er(e,t,n,c){const a=Jt(t,e,c,!0);ya(()=>{Pn(c[t],a)},n)}function Jt(e,t,n=ce,c=!1){if(n){const a=n[e]||(n[e]=[]),i=t.__weh||(t.__weh=(...r)=>{Fe();const s=Xt(n),f=Ie(t,n,e,r);return s(),Le(),f});return c?a.unshift(i):a.push(i),i}}const Ne=e=>(t,n=ce)=>{(!en||e==="sp")&&Jt(e,(...c)=>t(...c),n)},tr=Ne("bm"),Kn=Ne("m"),nr=Ne("bu"),cr=Ne("u"),ar=Ne("bum"),ya=Ne("um"),ir=Ne("sp"),rr=Ne("rtg"),or=Ne("rtc");function sr(e,t=ce){Jt("ec",e,t)}const dr=Symbol.for("v-ndc");function bc(e,t,n={},c,a){if(oe.isCE||oe.parent&&pt(oe.parent)&&oe.parent.isCE)return t!=="default"&&(n.name=t),ge("slot",n,c);let i=e[t];i&&i._c&&(i._d=!1),_t();const r=i&&Xa(i(n)),s=Ha(pe,{key:(n.key||r&&r.key||`_${t}`)+(!r&&c?"_fb":"")},r||[],r&&e._===1?64:-2);return i&&i._c&&(i._d=!0),s}function Xa(e){return e.some(t=>Da(t)?!(t.type===Me||t.type===pe&&!Xa(t.children)):!0)?e:null}const Vn=e=>e?Ka(e)?Gn(e):Vn(e.parent):null,ht=ae(Object.create(null),{$:e=>e,$el:e=>e.vnode.el,$data:e=>e.data,$props:e=>e.props,$attrs:e=>e.attrs,$slots:e=>e.slots,$refs:e=>e.refs,$parent:e=>Vn(e.parent),$root:e=>Vn(e.root),$emit:e=>e.emit,$options:e=>Un(e),$forceUpdate:e=>e.f||(e.f=()=>{e.effect.dirty=!0,Bn(e.update)}),$nextTick:e=>e.n||(e.n=ha.bind(e.proxy)),$watch:e=>Or.bind(e)}),sn=(e,t)=>e!==U&&!e.__isScriptSetup&&O(e,t),fr={get({_:e},t){if(t==="__v_skip")return!0;const{ctx:n,setupState:c,data:a,props:i,accessCache:r,type:s,appContext:f}=e;let b;if(t[0]!=="$"){const A=r[t];if(A!==void 0)switch(A){case 1:return c[t];case 2:return a[t];case 4:return n[t];case 3:return i[t]}else{if(sn(c,t))return r[t]=1,c[t];if(a!==U&&O(a,t))return r[t]=2,a[t];if((b=e.propsOptions[0])&&O(b,t))return r[t]=3,i[t];if(n!==U&&O(n,t))return r[t]=4,n[t];_n&&(r[t]=0)}}const l=ht[t];let g,y;if(l)return t==="$attrs"&&de(e.attrs,"get",""),l(e);if((g=s.__cssModules)&&(g=g[t]))return g;if(n!==U&&O(n,t))return r[t]=4,n[t];if(y=f.config.globalProperties,O(y,t))return y[t]},set({_:e},t,n){const{data:c,setupState:a,ctx:i}=e;return sn(a,t)?(a[t]=n,!0):c!==U&&O(c,t)?(c[t]=n,!0):O(e.props,t)||t[0]==="$"&&t.slice(1)in e?!1:(i[t]=n,!0)},has({_:{data:e,setupState:t,accessCache:n,ctx:c,appContext:a,propsOptions:i}},r){let s;return!!n[r]||e!==U&&O(e,r)||sn(t,r)||(s=i[0])&&O(s,r)||O(c,r)||O(ht,r)||O(a.config.globalProperties,r)},defineProperty(e,t,n){return n.get!=null?e._.accessCache[t]=0:O(n,"value")&&this.set(e,t,n.value,null),Reflect.defineProperty(e,t,n)}};function uc(e){return w(e)?e.reduce((t,n)=>(t[n]=null,t),{}):e}let _n=!0;function lr(e){const t=Un(e),n=e.proxy,c=e.ctx;_n=!1,t.beforeCreate&&pc(t.beforeCreate,e,"bc");const{data:a,computed:i,methods:r,watch:s,provide:f,inject:b,created:l,beforeMount:g,mounted:y,beforeUpdate:A,updated:L,activated:E,deactivated:Y,beforeDestroy:B,beforeUnmount:W,destroyed:T,unmounted:Z,render:K,renderTracked:M,renderTriggered:ie,errorCaptured:S,serverPrefetch:F,expose:J,inheritAttrs:ue,components:ke,directives:Ae,filters:ot}=t;if(b&&br(b,c,null),r)for(const P in r){const H=r[P];x(H)&&(c[P]=H.bind(n))}if(a){const P=a.call(n,n);z(P)&&(e.data=Wt(P))}if(_n=!0,i)for(const P in i){const H=i[P],qe=x(H)?H.bind(n,n):x(H.get)?H.get.bind(n,n):he,wt=!x(H)&&x(H.set)?H.set.bind(n):he,$e=za({get:qe,set:wt});Object.defineProperty(c,P,{enumerable:!0,configurable:!0,get:()=>$e.value,set:ve=>$e.value=ve})}if(s)for(const P in s)ja(s[P],c,n,P);if(f){const P=x(f)?f.call(n):f;Reflect.ownKeys(P).forEach(H=>{gr(H,P[H])})}l&&pc(l,e,"c");function G(P,H){w(H)?H.forEach(qe=>P(qe.bind(n))):H&&P(H.bind(n))}if(G(tr,g),G(Kn,y),G(nr,A),G(cr,L),G(Yi,E),G(Qi,Y),G(sr,S),G(or,M),G(rr,ie),G(ar,W),G(ya,Z),G(ir,F),w(J))if(J.length){const P=e.exposed||(e.exposed={});J.forEach(H=>{Object.defineProperty(P,H,{get:()=>n[H],set:qe=>n[H]=qe})})}else e.exposed||(e.exposed={});K&&e.render===he&&(e.render=K),ue!=null&&(e.inheritAttrs=ue),ke&&(e.components=ke),Ae&&(e.directives=Ae)}function br(e,t,n=he){w(e)&&(e=yn(e));for(const c in e){const a=e[c];let i;z(a)?"default"in a?i=mt(a.from||c,a.default,!0):i=mt(a.from||c):i=mt(a),Q(i)?Object.defineProperty(t,c,{enumerable:!0,configurable:!0,get:()=>i.value,set:r=>i.value=r}):t[c]=i}}function pc(e,t,n){Ie(w(e)?e.map(c=>c.bind(t.proxy)):e.bind(t.proxy),t,n)}function ja(e,t,n,c){const a=c.includes(".")?La(n,c):()=>n[c];if(te(e)){const i=t[e];x(i)&&Mt(a,i)}else if(x(e))Mt(a,e.bind(n));else if(z(e))if(w(e))e.forEach(i=>ja(i,t,n,c));else{const i=x(e.handler)?e.handler.bind(n):t[e.handler];x(i)&&Mt(a,i,e)}}function Un(e){const t=e.type,{mixins:n,extends:c}=t,{mixins:a,optionsCache:i,config:{optionMergeStrategies:r}}=e.appContext,s=i.get(t);let f;return s?f=s:!a.length&&!n&&!c?f=t:(f={},a.length&&a.forEach(b=>$t(f,b,r,!0)),$t(f,t,r)),z(t)&&i.set(t,f),f}function $t(e,t,n,c=!1){const{mixins:a,extends:i}=t;i&&$t(e,i,n,!0),a&&a.forEach(r=>$t(e,r,n,!0));for(const r in t)if(!(c&&r==="expose")){const s=ur[r]||n&&n[r];e[r]=s?s(e[r],t[r]):t[r]}return e}const ur={data:hc,props:mc,emits:mc,methods:bt,computed:bt,beforeCreate:re,created:re,beforeMount:re,mounted:re,beforeUpdate:re,updated:re,beforeDestroy:re,beforeUnmount:re,destroyed:re,unmounted:re,activated:re,deactivated:re,errorCaptured:re,serverPrefetch:re,components:bt,directives:bt,watch:hr,provide:hc,inject:pr};function hc(e,t){return t?e?function(){return ae(x(e)?e.call(this,this):e,x(t)?t.call(this,this):t)}:t:e}function pr(e,t){return bt(yn(e),yn(t))}function yn(e){if(w(e)){const t={};for(let n=0;n<e.length;n++)t[e[n]]=e[n];return t}return e}function re(e,t){return e?[...new Set([].concat(e,t))]:t}function bt(e,t){return e?ae(Object.create(null),e,t):t}function mc(e,t){return e?w(e)&&w(t)?[...new Set([...e,...t])]:ae(Object.create(null),uc(e),uc(t??{})):t}function hr(e,t){if(!e)return t;if(!t)return e;const n=ae(Object.create(null),e);for(const c in t)n[c]=re(e[c],t[c]);return n}function wa(){return{app:null,config:{isNativeTag:ci,performance:!1,globalProperties:{},optionMergeStrategies:{},errorHandler:void 0,warnHandler:void 0,compilerOptions:{}},mixins:[],components:{},directives:{},provides:Object.create(null),optionsCache:new WeakMap,propsCache:new WeakMap,emitsCache:new WeakMap}}let mr=0;function Ir(e,t){return function(c,a=null){x(c)||(c=ae({},c)),a!=null&&!z(a)&&(a=null);const i=wa(),r=new WeakSet;let s=!1;const f=i.app={_uid:mr++,_component:c,_props:a,_container:null,_context:i,_instance:null,version:co,get config(){return i.config},set config(b){},use(b,...l){return r.has(b)||(b&&x(b.install)?(r.add(b),b.install(f,...l)):x(b)&&(r.add(b),b(f,...l))),f},mixin(b){return i.mixins.includes(b)||i.mixins.push(b),f},component(b,l){return l?(i.components[b]=l,f):i.components[b]},directive(b,l){return l?(i.directives[b]=l,f):i.directives[b]},mount(b,l,g){if(!s){const y=ge(c,a);return y.appContext=i,g===!0?g="svg":g===!1&&(g=void 0),l&&t?t(y,b):e(y,b,g),s=!0,f._container=b,b.__vue_app__=f,Gn(y.component)}},unmount(){s&&(e(null,f._container),delete f._container.__vue_app__)},provide(b,l){return i.provides[b]=l,f},runWithContext(b){const l=at;at=f;try{return b()}finally{at=l}}};return f}}let at=null;function gr(e,t){if(ce){let n=ce.provides;const c=ce.parent&&ce.parent.provides;c===n&&(n=ce.provides=Object.create(c)),n[e]=t}}function mt(e,t,n=!1){const c=ce||oe;if(c||at){const a=c?c.parent==null?c.vnode.appContext&&c.vnode.appContext.provides:c.parent.provides:at._context.provides;if(a&&e in a)return a[e];if(arguments.length>1)return n&&x(t)?t.call(c&&c.proxy):t}}function kr(){return!!(ce||oe||at)}const Na={},Aa=()=>Object.create(Na),xa=e=>Object.getPrototypeOf(e)===Na;function vr(e,t,n,c=!1){const a={},i=Aa();e.propsDefaults=Object.create(null),Ca(e,t,a,i);for(const r in e.propsOptions[0])r in a||(a[r]=void 0);n?e.props=c?a:Ri(a):e.type.props?e.props=a:e.props=i,e.attrs=i}function Vr(e,t,n,c){const{props:a,attrs:i,vnode:{patchFlag:r}}=e,s=R(a),[f]=e.propsOptions;let b=!1;if((c||r>0)&&!(r&16)){if(r&8){const l=e.vnode.dynamicProps;for(let g=0;g<l.length;g++){let y=l[g];if(Yt(e.emitsOptions,y))continue;const A=t[y];if(f)if(O(i,y))A!==i[y]&&(i[y]=A,b=!0);else{const L=Ge(y);a[L]=Xn(f,s,L,A,e,!1)}else A!==i[y]&&(i[y]=A,b=!0)}}}else{Ca(e,t,a,i)&&(b=!0);let l;for(const g in s)(!t||!O(t,g)&&((l=Je(g))===g||!O(t,l)))&&(f?n&&(n[g]!==void 0||n[l]!==void 0)&&(a[g]=Xn(f,s,g,void 0,e,!0)):delete a[g]);if(i!==s)for(const g in i)(!t||!O(t,g))&&(delete i[g],b=!0)}b&&we(e.attrs,"set","")}function Ca(e,t,n,c){const[a,i]=e.propsOptions;let r=!1,s;if(t)for(let f in t){if(ut(f))continue;const b=t[f];let l;a&&O(a,l=Ge(f))?!i||!i.includes(l)?n[l]=b:(s||(s={}))[l]=b:Yt(e.emitsOptions,f)||(!(f in c)||b!==c[f])&&(c[f]=b,r=!0)}if(i){const f=R(n),b=s||U;for(let l=0;l<i.length;l++){const g=i[l];n[g]=Xn(a,f,g,b[g],e,!O(b,g))}}return r}function Xn(e,t,n,c,a,i){const r=e[n];if(r!=null){const s=O(r,"default");if(s&&c===void 0){const f=r.default;if(r.type!==Function&&!r.skipFactory&&x(f)){const{propsDefaults:b}=a;if(n in b)c=b[n];else{const l=Xt(a);c=b[n]=f.call(null,t),l()}}else c=f}r[0]&&(i&&!s?c=!1:r[1]&&(c===""||c===Je(n))&&(c=!0))}return c}const _r=new WeakMap;function Sa(e,t,n=!1){const c=n?_r:t.propsCache,a=c.get(e);if(a)return a;const i=e.props,r={},s=[];let f=!1;if(!x(e)){const l=g=>{f=!0;const[y,A]=Sa(g,t,!0);ae(r,y),A&&s.push(...A)};!n&&t.mixins.length&&t.mixins.forEach(l),e.extends&&l(e.extends),e.mixins&&e.mixins.forEach(l)}if(!i&&!f)return z(e)&&c.set(e,et),et;if(w(i))for(let l=0;l<i.length;l++){const g=Ge(i[l]);Ic(g)&&(r[g]=U)}else if(i)for(const l in i){const g=Ge(l);if(Ic(g)){const y=i[l],A=r[g]=w(y)||x(y)?{type:y}:ae({},y),L=A.type;let E=!1,Y=!0;if(w(L))for(let B=0;B<L.length;++B){const W=L[B],T=x(W)&&W.name;if(T==="Boolean"){E=!0;break}else T==="String"&&(Y=!1)}else E=x(L)&&L.name==="Boolean";A[0]=E,A[1]=Y,(E||O(A,"default"))&&s.push(g)}}const b=[r,s];return z(e)&&c.set(e,b),b}function Ic(e){return e[0]!=="$"&&!ut(e)}const Pa=e=>e[0]==="_"||e==="$stable",zn=e=>w(e)?e.map(ye):[ye(e)],yr=(e,t,n)=>{if(t._n)return t;const c=vn((...a)=>zn(t(...a)),n);return c._c=!1,c},Ea=(e,t,n)=>{const c=e._ctx;for(const a in e){if(Pa(a))continue;const i=e[a];if(x(i))t[a]=yr(a,i,c);else if(i!=null){const r=zn(i);t[a]=()=>r}}},Oa=(e,t)=>{const n=zn(t);e.slots.default=()=>n},Ta=(e,t,n)=>{for(const c in t)(n||c!=="_")&&(e[c]=t[c])},Xr=(e,t,n)=>{const c=e.slots=Aa();if(e.vnode.shapeFlag&32){const a=t._;a?(Ta(c,t,n),n&&Dc(c,"_",a,!0)):Ea(t,c)}else t&&Oa(e,t)},jr=(e,t,n)=>{const{vnode:c,slots:a}=e;let i=!0,r=U;if(c.shapeFlag&32){const s=t._;s?n&&s===1?i=!1:Ta(a,t,n):(i=!t.$stable,Ea(t,a)),r=t}else t&&(Oa(e,t),r={default:1});if(i)for(const s in a)!Pa(s)&&r[s]==null&&delete a[s]};function jn(e,t,n,c,a=!1){if(w(e)){e.forEach((y,A)=>jn(y,t&&(w(t)?t[A]:t),n,c,a));return}if(pt(c)&&!a)return;const i=c.shapeFlag&4?Gn(c.component):c.el,r=a?null:i,{i:s,r:f}=e,b=t&&t.r,l=s.refs===U?s.refs={}:s.refs,g=s.setupState;if(b!=null&&b!==f&&(te(b)?(l[b]=null,O(g,b)&&(g[b]=null)):Q(b)&&(b.value=null)),x(f))Oe(f,s,12,[r,l]);else{const y=te(f),A=Q(f);if(y||A){const L=()=>{if(e.f){const E=y?O(g,f)?g[f]:l[f]:f.value;a?w(E)&&Pn(E,i):w(E)?E.includes(i)||E.push(i):y?(l[f]=[i],O(g,f)&&(g[f]=l[f])):(f.value=[i],e.k&&(l[e.k]=f.value))}else y?(l[f]=r,O(g,f)&&(g[f]=r)):A&&(f.value=r,e.k&&(l[e.k]=r))};r?(L.id=-1,se(L,n)):L()}}}const wr=Symbol("_vte"),Nr=e=>e.__isTeleport,se=Hr;function Ar(e){return xr(e)}function xr(e,t){const n=Bc();n.__VUE__=!0;const{insert:c,remove:a,patchProp:i,createElement:r,createText:s,createComment:f,setText:b,setElementText:l,parentNode:g,nextSibling:y,setScopeId:A=he,insertStaticContent:L}=e,E=(o,d,u,m=null,p=null,I=null,V=void 0,k=null,v=!!d.dynamicChildren)=>{if(o===d)return;o&&!lt(o,d)&&(m=Nt(o),ve(o,p,I,!0),o=null),d.patchFlag===-2&&(v=!1,d.dynamicChildren=null);const{type:h,ref:_,shapeFlag:j}=d;switch(h){case Qt:Y(o,d,u,m);break;case Me:B(o,d,u,m);break;case ln:o==null&&W(d,u,m,V);break;case pe:ke(o,d,u,m,p,I,V,k,v);break;default:j&1?K(o,d,u,m,p,I,V,k,v):j&6?Ae(o,d,u,m,p,I,V,k,v):(j&64||j&128)&&h.process(o,d,u,m,p,I,V,k,v,dt)}_!=null&&p&&jn(_,o&&o.ref,I,d||o,!d)},Y=(o,d,u,m)=>{if(o==null)c(d.el=s(d.children),u,m);else{const p=d.el=o.el;d.children!==o.children&&b(p,d.children)}},B=(o,d,u,m)=>{o==null?c(d.el=f(d.children||""),u,m):d.el=o.el},W=(o,d,u,m)=>{[o.el,o.anchor]=L(o.children,d,u,m,o.el,o.anchor)},T=({el:o,anchor:d},u,m)=>{let p;for(;o&&o!==d;)p=y(o),c(o,u,m),o=p;c(d,u,m)},Z=({el:o,anchor:d})=>{let u;for(;o&&o!==d;)u=y(o),a(o),o=u;a(d)},K=(o,d,u,m,p,I,V,k,v)=>{d.type==="svg"?V="svg":d.type==="math"&&(V="mathml"),o==null?M(d,u,m,p,I,V,k,v):F(o,d,p,I,V,k,v)},M=(o,d,u,m,p,I,V,k)=>{let v,h;const{props:_,shapeFlag:j,transition:X,dirs:N}=o;if(v=o.el=r(o.type,I,_&&_.is,_),j&8?l(v,o.children):j&16&&S(o.children,v,null,m,p,dn(o,I),V,k),N&&He(o,null,m,"created"),ie(v,o,o.scopeId,V,m),_){for(const D in _)D!=="value"&&!ut(D)&&i(v,D,null,_[D],I,m);"value"in _&&i(v,"value",null,_.value,I),(h=_.onVnodeBeforeMount)&&_e(h,m,o)}N&&He(o,null,m,"beforeMount");const C=Cr(p,X);C&&X.beforeEnter(v),c(v,d,u),((h=_&&_.onVnodeMounted)||C||N)&&se(()=>{h&&_e(h,m,o),C&&X.enter(v),N&&He(o,null,m,"mounted")},p)},ie=(o,d,u,m,p)=>{if(u&&A(o,u),m)for(let I=0;I<m.length;I++)A(o,m[I]);if(p){let I=p.subTree;if(d===I){const V=p.vnode;ie(o,V,V.scopeId,V.slotScopeIds,p.parent)}}},S=(o,d,u,m,p,I,V,k,v=0)=>{for(let h=v;h<o.length;h++){const _=o[h]=k?Pe(o[h]):ye(o[h]);E(null,_,d,u,m,p,I,V,k)}},F=(o,d,u,m,p,I,V)=>{const k=d.el=o.el;let{patchFlag:v,dynamicChildren:h,dirs:_}=d;v|=o.patchFlag&16;const j=o.props||U,X=d.props||U;let N;if(u&&De(u,!1),(N=X.onVnodeBeforeUpdate)&&_e(N,u,d,o),_&&He(d,o,u,"beforeUpdate"),u&&De(u,!0),(j.innerHTML&&X.innerHTML==null||j.textContent&&X.textContent==null)&&l(k,""),h?J(o.dynamicChildren,h,k,u,m,dn(d,p),I):V||H(o,d,k,null,u,m,dn(d,p),I,!1),v>0){if(v&16)ue(k,j,X,u,p);else if(v&2&&j.class!==X.class&&i(k,"class",null,X.class,p),v&4&&i(k,"style",j.style,X.style,p),v&8){const C=d.dynamicProps;for(let D=0;D<C.length;D++){const q=C[D],ee=j[q],me=X[q];(me!==ee||q==="value")&&i(k,q,ee,me,p,u)}}v&1&&o.children!==d.children&&l(k,d.children)}else!V&&h==null&&ue(k,j,X,u,p);((N=X.onVnodeUpdated)||_)&&se(()=>{N&&_e(N,u,d,o),_&&He(d,o,u,"updated")},m)},J=(o,d,u,m,p,I,V)=>{for(let k=0;k<d.length;k++){const v=o[k],h=d[k],_=v.el&&(v.type===pe||!lt(v,h)||v.shapeFlag&70)?g(v.el):u;E(v,h,_,null,m,p,I,V,!0)}},ue=(o,d,u,m,p)=>{if(d!==u){if(d!==U)for(const I in d)!ut(I)&&!(I in u)&&i(o,I,d[I],null,p,m);for(const I in u){if(ut(I))continue;const V=u[I],k=d[I];V!==k&&I!=="value"&&i(o,I,k,V,p,m)}"value"in u&&i(o,"value",d.value,u.value,p)}},ke=(o,d,u,m,p,I,V,k,v)=>{const h=d.el=o?o.el:s(""),_=d.anchor=o?o.anchor:s("");let{patchFlag:j,dynamicChildren:X,slotScopeIds:N}=d;N&&(k=k?k.concat(N):N),o==null?(c(h,u,m),c(_,u,m),S(d.children||[],u,_,p,I,V,k,v)):j>0&&j&64&&X&&o.dynamicChildren?(J(o.dynamicChildren,X,u,p,I,V,k),(d.key!=null||p&&d===p.subTree)&&Ma(o,d,!0)):H(o,d,u,_,p,I,V,k,v)},Ae=(o,d,u,m,p,I,V,k,v)=>{d.slotScopeIds=k,o==null?d.shapeFlag&512?p.ctx.activate(d,u,m,V,v):ot(d,u,m,p,I,V,v):jt(o,d,v)},ot=(o,d,u,m,p,I,V)=>{const k=o.component=Jr(o,m,p);if(Va(o)&&(k.ctx.renderer=dt),Yr(k,!1,V),k.asyncDep){if(p&&p.registerDep(k,G,V),!o.el){const v=k.subTree=ge(Me);B(null,v,d,u)}}else G(k,o,d,u,p,I,V)},jt=(o,d,u)=>{const m=d.component=o.component;if(Lr(o,d,u))if(m.asyncDep&&!m.asyncResolved){P(m,d,u);return}else m.next=d,zi(m.update),m.effect.dirty=!0,m.update();else d.el=o.el,m.vnode=d},G=(o,d,u,m,p,I,V)=>{const k=()=>{if(o.isMounted){let{next:_,bu:j,u:X,parent:N,vnode:C}=o;{const Ye=Ra(o);if(Ye){_&&(_.el=C.el,P(o,_,V)),Ye.asyncDep.then(()=>{o.isUnmounted||k()});return}}let D=_,q;De(o,!1),_?(_.el=C.el,P(o,_,V)):_=C,j&&rn(j),(q=_.props&&_.props.onVnodeBeforeUpdate)&&_e(q,N,_,C),De(o,!0);const ee=fn(o),me=o.subTree;o.subTree=ee,E(me,ee,g(me.el),Nt(me),o,p,I),_.el=ee.el,D===null&&qr(o,ee.el),X&&se(X,p),(q=_.props&&_.props.onVnodeUpdated)&&se(()=>_e(q,N,_,C),p)}else{let _;const{el:j,props:X}=d,{bm:N,m:C,parent:D}=o,q=pt(d);if(De(o,!1),N&&rn(N),!q&&(_=X&&X.onVnodeBeforeMount)&&_e(_,D,d),De(o,!0),j&&Qn){const ee=()=>{o.subTree=fn(o),Qn(j,o.subTree,o,p,null)};q?d.type.__asyncLoader().then(()=>!o.isUnmounted&&ee()):ee()}else{const ee=o.subTree=fn(o);E(null,ee,u,m,o,p,I),d.el=ee.el}if(C&&se(C,p),!q&&(_=X&&X.onVnodeMounted)){const ee=d;se(()=>_e(_,D,ee),p)}(d.shapeFlag&256||D&&pt(D.vnode)&&D.vnode.shapeFlag&256)&&o.a&&se(o.a,p),o.isMounted=!0,d=u=m=null}},v=o.effect=new Tn(k,he,()=>Bn(h),o.scope),h=o.update=()=>{v.dirty&&v.run()};h.i=o,h.id=o.uid,De(o,!0),h()},P=(o,d,u)=>{d.component=o;const m=o.vnode.props;o.vnode=d,o.next=null,Vr(o,d.props,m,u),jr(o,d.children,u),Fe(),lc(o),Le()},H=(o,d,u,m,p,I,V,k,v=!1)=>{const h=o&&o.children,_=o?o.shapeFlag:0,j=d.children,{patchFlag:X,shapeFlag:N}=d;if(X>0){if(X&128){wt(h,j,u,m,p,I,V,k,v);return}else if(X&256){qe(h,j,u,m,p,I,V,k,v);return}}N&8?(_&16&&st(h,p,I),j!==h&&l(u,j)):_&16?N&16?wt(h,j,u,m,p,I,V,k,v):st(h,p,I,!0):(_&8&&l(u,""),N&16&&S(j,u,m,p,I,V,k,v))},qe=(o,d,u,m,p,I,V,k,v)=>{o=o||et,d=d||et;const h=o.length,_=d.length,j=Math.min(h,_);let X;for(X=0;X<j;X++){const N=d[X]=v?Pe(d[X]):ye(d[X]);E(o[X],N,u,null,p,I,V,k,v)}h>_?st(o,p,I,!0,!1,j):S(d,u,m,p,I,V,k,v,j)},wt=(o,d,u,m,p,I,V,k,v)=>{let h=0;const _=d.length;let j=o.length-1,X=_-1;for(;h<=j&&h<=X;){const N=o[h],C=d[h]=v?Pe(d[h]):ye(d[h]);if(lt(N,C))E(N,C,u,null,p,I,V,k,v);else break;h++}for(;h<=j&&h<=X;){const N=o[j],C=d[X]=v?Pe(d[X]):ye(d[X]);if(lt(N,C))E(N,C,u,null,p,I,V,k,v);else break;j--,X--}if(h>j){if(h<=X){const N=X+1,C=N<_?d[N].el:m;for(;h<=X;)E(null,d[h]=v?Pe(d[h]):ye(d[h]),u,C,p,I,V,k,v),h++}}else if(h>X)for(;h<=j;)ve(o[h],p,I,!0),h++;else{const N=h,C=h,D=new Map;for(h=C;h<=X;h++){const fe=d[h]=v?Pe(d[h]):ye(d[h]);fe.key!=null&&D.set(fe.key,h)}let q,ee=0;const me=X-C+1;let Ye=!1,ec=0;const ft=new Array(me);for(h=0;h<me;h++)ft[h]=0;for(h=N;h<=j;h++){const fe=o[h];if(ee>=me){ve(fe,p,I,!0);continue}let Ve;if(fe.key!=null)Ve=D.get(fe.key);else for(q=C;q<=X;q++)if(ft[q-C]===0&&lt(fe,d[q])){Ve=q;break}Ve===void 0?ve(fe,p,I,!0):(ft[Ve-C]=h+1,Ve>=ec?ec=Ve:Ye=!0,E(fe,d[Ve],u,null,p,I,V,k,v),ee++)}const tc=Ye?Sr(ft):et;for(q=tc.length-1,h=me-1;h>=0;h--){const fe=C+h,Ve=d[fe],nc=fe+1<_?d[fe+1].el:m;ft[h]===0?E(null,Ve,u,nc,p,I,V,k,v):Ye&&(q<0||h!==tc[q]?$e(Ve,u,nc,2):q--)}}},$e=(o,d,u,m,p=null)=>{const{el:I,type:V,transition:k,children:v,shapeFlag:h}=o;if(h&6){$e(o.component.subTree,d,u,m);return}if(h&128){o.suspense.move(d,u,m);return}if(h&64){V.move(o,d,u,dt);return}if(V===pe){c(I,d,u);for(let j=0;j<v.length;j++)$e(v[j],d,u,m);c(o.anchor,d,u);return}if(V===ln){T(o,d,u);return}if(m!==2&&h&1&&k)if(m===0)k.beforeEnter(I),c(I,d,u),se(()=>k.enter(I),p);else{const{leave:j,delayLeave:X,afterLeave:N}=k,C=()=>c(I,d,u),D=()=>{j(I,()=>{C(),N&&N()})};X?X(I,C,D):D()}else c(I,d,u)},ve=(o,d,u,m=!1,p=!1)=>{const{type:I,props:V,ref:k,children:v,dynamicChildren:h,shapeFlag:_,patchFlag:j,dirs:X,cacheIndex:N}=o;if(j===-2&&(p=!1),k!=null&&jn(k,null,u,o,!0),N!=null&&(d.renderCache[N]=void 0),_&256){d.ctx.deactivate(o);return}const C=_&1&&X,D=!pt(o);let q;if(D&&(q=V&&V.onVnodeBeforeUnmount)&&_e(q,d,o),_&6)ni(o.component,u,m);else{if(_&128){o.suspense.unmount(u,m);return}C&&He(o,null,d,"beforeUnmount"),_&64?o.type.remove(o,d,u,dt,m):h&&!h.hasOnce&&(I!==pe||j>0&&j&64)?st(h,d,u,!1,!0):(I===pe&&j&384||!p&&_&16)&&st(v,d,u),m&&Zn(o)}(D&&(q=V&&V.onVnodeUnmounted)||C)&&se(()=>{q&&_e(q,d,o),C&&He(o,null,d,"unmounted")},u)},Zn=o=>{const{type:d,el:u,anchor:m,transition:p}=o;if(d===pe){ti(u,m);return}if(d===ln){Z(o);return}const I=()=>{a(u),p&&!p.persisted&&p.afterLeave&&p.afterLeave()};if(o.shapeFlag&1&&p&&!p.persisted){const{leave:V,delayLeave:k}=p,v=()=>V(u,I);k?k(o.el,I,v):v()}else I()},ti=(o,d)=>{let u;for(;o!==d;)u=y(o),a(o),o=u;a(d)},ni=(o,d,u)=>{const{bum:m,scope:p,update:I,subTree:V,um:k,m:v,a:h}=o;gc(v),gc(h),m&&rn(m),p.stop(),I&&(I.active=!1,ve(V,o,d,u)),k&&se(k,d),se(()=>{o.isUnmounted=!0},d),d&&d.pendingBranch&&!d.isUnmounted&&o.asyncDep&&!o.asyncResolved&&o.suspenseId===d.pendingId&&(d.deps--,d.deps===0&&d.resolve())},st=(o,d,u,m=!1,p=!1,I=0)=>{for(let V=I;V<o.length;V++)ve(o[V],d,u,m,p)},Nt=o=>{if(o.shapeFlag&6)return Nt(o.component.subTree);if(o.shapeFlag&128)return o.suspense.next();const d=y(o.anchor||o.el),u=d&&d[wr];return u?y(u):d};let cn=!1;const Jn=(o,d,u)=>{o==null?d._vnode&&ve(d._vnode,null,null,!0):E(d._vnode||null,o,d,null,null,null,u),cn||(cn=!0,lc(),Ia(),cn=!1),d._vnode=o},dt={p:E,um:ve,m:$e,r:Zn,mt:ot,mc:S,pc:H,pbc:J,n:Nt,o:e};let Yn,Qn;return{render:Jn,hydrate:Yn,createApp:Ir(Jn,Yn)}}function dn({type:e,props:t},n){return n==="svg"&&e==="foreignObject"||n==="mathml"&&e==="annotation-xml"&&t&&t.encoding&&t.encoding.includes("html")?void 0:n}function De({effect:e,update:t},n){e.allowRecurse=t.allowRecurse=n}function Cr(e,t){return(!e||e&&!e.pendingBranch)&&t&&!t.persisted}function Ma(e,t,n=!1){const c=e.children,a=t.children;if(w(c)&&w(a))for(let i=0;i<c.length;i++){const r=c[i];let s=a[i];s.shapeFlag&1&&!s.dynamicChildren&&((s.patchFlag<=0||s.patchFlag===32)&&(s=a[i]=Pe(a[i]),s.el=r.el),!n&&s.patchFlag!==-2&&Ma(r,s)),s.type===Qt&&(s.el=r.el)}}function Sr(e){const t=e.slice(),n=[0];let c,a,i,r,s;const f=e.length;for(c=0;c<f;c++){const b=e[c];if(b!==0){if(a=n[n.length-1],e[a]<b){t[c]=a,n.push(c);continue}for(i=0,r=n.length-1;i<r;)s=i+r>>1,e[n[s]]<b?i=s+1:r=s;b<e[n[i]]&&(i>0&&(t[c]=n[i-1]),n[i]=c)}}for(i=n.length,r=n[i-1];i-- >0;)n[i]=r,r=t[r];return n}function Ra(e){const t=e.subTree.component;if(t)return t.asyncDep&&!t.asyncResolved?t:Ra(t)}function gc(e){if(e)for(let t=0;t<e.length;t++)e[t].active=!1}const Pr=Symbol.for("v-scx"),Er=()=>mt(Pr),Et={};function Mt(e,t,n){return Fa(e,t,n)}function Fa(e,t,{immediate:n,deep:c,flush:a,once:i,onTrack:r,onTrigger:s}=U){if(t&&i){const M=t;t=(...ie)=>{M(...ie),K()}}const f=ce,b=M=>c===!0?M:Ke(M,c===!1?1:void 0);let l,g=!1,y=!1;if(Q(e)?(l=()=>e.value,g=it(e)):We(e)?(l=()=>b(e),g=!0):w(e)?(y=!0,g=e.some(M=>We(M)||it(M)),l=()=>e.map(M=>{if(Q(M))return M.value;if(We(M))return b(M);if(x(M))return Oe(M,f,2)})):x(e)?t?l=()=>Oe(e,f,2):l=()=>(A&&A(),Ie(e,f,3,[L])):l=he,t&&c){const M=l;l=()=>Ke(M())}let A,L=M=>{A=T.onStop=()=>{Oe(M,f,4),A=T.onStop=void 0}},E;if(en)if(L=he,t?n&&Ie(t,f,3,[l(),y?[]:void 0,L]):l(),a==="sync"){const M=Er();E=M.__watcherHandles||(M.__watcherHandles=[])}else return he;let Y=y?new Array(e.length).fill(Et):Et;const B=()=>{if(!(!T.active||!T.dirty))if(t){const M=T.run();(c||g||(y?M.some((ie,S)=>Te(ie,Y[S])):Te(M,Y)))&&(A&&A(),Ie(t,f,3,[M,Y===Et?void 0:y&&Y[0]===Et?[]:Y,L]),Y=M)}else T.run()};B.allowRecurse=!!t;let W;a==="sync"?W=B:a==="post"?W=()=>se(B,f&&f.suspense):(B.pre=!0,f&&(B.id=f.uid),W=()=>Bn(B));const T=new Tn(l,he,W),Z=Zc(),K=()=>{T.stop(),Z&&Pn(Z.effects,T)};return t?n?B():Y=T.run():a==="post"?se(T.run.bind(T),f&&f.suspense):T.run(),E&&E.push(K),K}function Or(e,t,n){const c=this.proxy,a=te(e)?e.includes(".")?La(c,e):()=>c[e]:e.bind(c,c);let i;x(t)?i=t:(i=t.handler,n=t);const r=Xt(this),s=Fa(a,i.bind(c),n);return r(),s}function La(e,t){const n=t.split(".");return()=>{let c=e;for(let a=0;a<n.length&&c;a++)c=c[n[a]];return c}}function Ke(e,t=1/0,n){if(t<=0||!z(e)||e.__v_skip||(n=n||new Set,n.has(e)))return e;if(n.add(e),t--,Q(e))Ke(e.value,t,n);else if(w(e))for(let c=0;c<e.length;c++)Ke(e[c],t,n);else if(Fc(e)||tt(e))e.forEach(c=>{Ke(c,t,n)});else if($c(e)){for(const c in e)Ke(e[c],t,n);for(const c of Object.getOwnPropertySymbols(e))Object.prototype.propertyIsEnumerable.call(e,c)&&Ke(e[c],t,n)}return e}const Tr=(e,t)=>t==="modelValue"||t==="model-value"?e.modelModifiers:e[`${t}Modifiers`]||e[`${Ge(t)}Modifiers`]||e[`${Je(t)}Modifiers`];function Mr(e,t,...n){if(e.isUnmounted)return;const c=e.vnode.props||U;let a=n;const i=t.startsWith("update:"),r=i&&Tr(c,t.slice(7));r&&(r.trim&&(a=n.map(l=>te(l)?l.trim():l)),r.number&&(a=n.map(si)));let s,f=c[s=an(t)]||c[s=an(Ge(t))];!f&&i&&(f=c[s=an(Je(t))]),f&&Ie(f,e,6,a);const b=c[s+"Once"];if(b){if(!e.emitted)e.emitted={};else if(e.emitted[s])return;e.emitted[s]=!0,Ie(b,e,6,a)}}function qa(e,t,n=!1){const c=t.emitsCache,a=c.get(e);if(a!==void 0)return a;const i=e.emits;let r={},s=!1;if(!x(e)){const f=b=>{const l=qa(b,t,!0);l&&(s=!0,ae(r,l))};!n&&t.mixins.length&&t.mixins.forEach(f),e.extends&&f(e.extends),e.mixins&&e.mixins.forEach(f)}return!i&&!s?(z(e)&&c.set(e,null),null):(w(i)?i.forEach(f=>r[f]=null):ae(r,i),z(e)&&c.set(e,r),r)}function Yt(e,t){return!e||!Dt(t)?!1:(t=t.slice(2).replace(/Once$/,""),O(e,t[0].toLowerCase()+t.slice(1))||O(e,Je(t))||O(e,t))}function fn(e){const{type:t,vnode:n,proxy:c,withProxy:a,propsOptions:[i],slots:r,attrs:s,emit:f,render:b,renderCache:l,props:g,data:y,setupState:A,ctx:L,inheritAttrs:E}=e,Y=qt(e);let B,W;try{if(n.shapeFlag&4){const Z=a||c,K=Z;B=ye(b.call(K,Z,l,g,A,y,L)),W=s}else{const Z=t;B=ye(Z.length>1?Z(g,{attrs:s,slots:r,emit:f}):Z(g,null)),W=t.props?s:Rr(s)}}catch(Z){It.length=0,Gt(Z,e,1),B=ge(Me)}let T=B;if(W&&E!==!1){const Z=Object.keys(W),{shapeFlag:K}=T;Z.length&&K&7&&(i&&Z.some(Sn)&&(W=Fr(W,i)),T=rt(T,W,!1,!0))}return n.dirs&&(T=rt(T,null,!1,!0),T.dirs=T.dirs?T.dirs.concat(n.dirs):n.dirs),n.transition&&(T.transition=n.transition),B=T,qt(Y),B}const Rr=e=>{let t;for(const n in e)(n==="class"||n==="style"||Dt(n))&&((t||(t={}))[n]=e[n]);return t},Fr=(e,t)=>{const n={};for(const c in e)(!Sn(c)||!(c.slice(9)in t))&&(n[c]=e[c]);return n};function Lr(e,t,n){const{props:c,children:a,component:i}=e,{props:r,children:s,patchFlag:f}=t,b=i.emitsOptions;if(t.dirs||t.transition)return!0;if(n&&f>=0){if(f&1024)return!0;if(f&16)return c?kc(c,r,b):!!r;if(f&8){const l=t.dynamicProps;for(let g=0;g<l.length;g++){const y=l[g];if(r[y]!==c[y]&&!Yt(b,y))return!0}}}else return(a||s)&&(!s||!s.$stable)?!0:c===r?!1:c?r?kc(c,r,b):!0:!!r;return!1}function kc(e,t,n){const c=Object.keys(t);if(c.length!==Object.keys(e).length)return!0;for(let a=0;a<c.length;a++){const i=c[a];if(t[i]!==e[i]&&!Yt(n,i))return!0}return!1}function qr({vnode:e,parent:t},n){for(;t;){const c=t.subTree;if(c.suspense&&c.suspense.activeBranch===e&&(c.el=e.el),c===e)(e=t.vnode).el=n,t=t.parent;else break}}const $r=e=>e.__isSuspense;function Hr(e,t){t&&t.pendingBranch?w(e)?t.effects.push(...e):t.effects.push(e):Wi(e)}const pe=Symbol.for("v-fgt"),Qt=Symbol.for("v-txt"),Me=Symbol.for("v-cmt"),ln=Symbol.for("v-stc"),It=[];let be=null;function _t(e=!1){It.push(be=e?null:[])}function Dr(){It.pop(),be=It[It.length-1]||null}let yt=1;function vc(e){yt+=e,e<0&&be&&(be.hasOnce=!0)}function $a(e){return e.dynamicChildren=yt>0?be||et:null,Dr(),yt>0&&be&&be.push(e),e}function wn(e,t,n,c,a,i){return $a($(e,t,n,c,a,i,!0))}function Ha(e,t,n,c,a){return $a(ge(e,t,n,c,a,!0))}function Da(e){return e?e.__v_isVNode===!0:!1}function lt(e,t){return e.type===t.type&&e.key===t.key}const Ba=({key:e})=>e??null,Rt=({ref:e,ref_key:t,ref_for:n})=>(typeof e=="number"&&(e=""+e),e!=null?te(e)||Q(e)||x(e)?{i:oe,r:e,k:t,f:!!n}:e:null);function $(e,t=null,n=null,c=0,a=null,i=e===pe?0:1,r=!1,s=!1){const f={__v_isVNode:!0,__v_skip:!0,type:e,props:t,key:t&&Ba(t),ref:t&&Rt(t),scopeId:Zt,slotScopeIds:null,children:n,component:null,suspense:null,ssContent:null,ssFallback:null,dirs:null,transition:null,el:null,anchor:null,target:null,targetStart:null,targetAnchor:null,staticCount:0,shapeFlag:i,patchFlag:c,dynamicProps:a,dynamicChildren:null,appContext:null,ctx:oe};return s?(Wn(f,n),i&128&&e.normalize(f)):n&&(f.shapeFlag|=te(n)?8:16),yt>0&&!r&&be&&(f.patchFlag>0||i&6)&&f.patchFlag!==32&&be.push(f),f}const ge=Br;function Br(e,t=null,n=null,c=0,a=null,i=!1){if((!e||e===dr)&&(e=Me),Da(e)){const s=rt(e,t,!0);return n&&Wn(s,n),yt>0&&!i&&be&&(s.shapeFlag&6?be[be.indexOf(e)]=s:be.push(s)),s.patchFlag=-2,s}if(no(e)&&(e=e.__vccOpts),t){t=Kr(t);let{class:s,style:f}=t;s&&!te(s)&&(t.class=Ut(s)),z(f)&&(da(f)&&!w(f)&&(f=ae({},f)),t.style=On(f))}const r=te(e)?1:$r(e)?128:Nr(e)?64:z(e)?4:x(e)?2:0;return $(e,t,n,c,a,r,i,!0)}function Kr(e){return e?da(e)||xa(e)?ae({},e):e:null}function rt(e,t,n=!1,c=!1){const{props:a,ref:i,patchFlag:r,children:s,transition:f}=e,b=t?Wr(a||{},t):a,l={__v_isVNode:!0,__v_skip:!0,type:e.type,props:b,key:b&&Ba(b),ref:t&&t.ref?n&&i?w(i)?i.concat(Rt(t)):[i,Rt(t)]:Rt(t):i,scopeId:e.scopeId,slotScopeIds:e.slotScopeIds,children:s,target:e.target,targetStart:e.targetStart,targetAnchor:e.targetAnchor,staticCount:e.staticCount,shapeFlag:e.shapeFlag,patchFlag:t&&e.type!==pe?r===-1?16:r|16:r,dynamicProps:e.dynamicProps,dynamicChildren:e.dynamicChildren,appContext:e.appContext,dirs:e.dirs,transition:f,component:e.component,suspense:e.suspense,ssContent:e.ssContent&&rt(e.ssContent),ssFallback:e.ssFallback&&rt(e.ssFallback),el:e.el,anchor:e.anchor,ctx:e.ctx,ce:e.ce};return f&&c&&ka(l,f.clone(l)),l}function Ur(e=" ",t=0){return ge(Qt,null,e,t)}function zr(e="",t=!1){return t?(_t(),Ha(Me,null,e)):ge(Me,null,e)}function ye(e){return e==null||typeof e=="boolean"?ge(Me):w(e)?ge(pe,null,e.slice()):typeof e=="object"?Pe(e):ge(Qt,null,String(e))}function Pe(e){return e.el===null&&e.patchFlag!==-1||e.memo?e:rt(e)}function Wn(e,t){let n=0;const{shapeFlag:c}=e;if(t==null)t=null;else if(w(t))n=16;else if(typeof t=="object")if(c&65){const a=t.default;a&&(a._c&&(a._d=!1),Wn(e,a()),a._c&&(a._d=!0));return}else{n=32;const a=t._;!a&&!xa(t)?t._ctx=oe:a===3&&oe&&(oe.slots._===1?t._=1:(t._=2,e.patchFlag|=1024))}else x(t)?(t={default:t,_ctx:oe},n=32):(t=String(t),c&64?(n=16,t=[Ur(t)]):n=8);e.children=t,e.shapeFlag|=n}function Wr(...e){const t={};for(let n=0;n<e.length;n++){const c=e[n];for(const a in c)if(a==="class")t.class!==c.class&&(t.class=Ut([t.class,c.class]));else if(a==="style")t.style=On([t.style,c.style]);else if(Dt(a)){const i=t[a],r=c[a];r&&i!==r&&!(w(i)&&i.includes(r))&&(t[a]=i?[].concat(i,r):r)}else a!==""&&(t[a]=c[a])}return t}function _e(e,t,n,c=null){Ie(e,t,7,[n,c])}const Gr=wa();let Zr=0;function Jr(e,t,n){const c=e.type,a=(t?t.appContext:e.appContext)||Gr,i={uid:Zr++,vnode:e,type:c,parent:t,appContext:a,root:null,next:null,subTree:null,effect:null,update:null,scope:new Wc(!0),render:null,proxy:null,exposed:null,exposeProxy:null,withProxy:null,provides:t?t.provides:Object.create(a.provides),accessCache:null,renderCache:[],components:null,directives:null,propsOptions:Sa(c,a),emitsOptions:qa(c,a),emit:null,emitted:null,propsDefaults:U,inheritAttrs:c.inheritAttrs,ctx:U,data:U,props:U,attrs:U,slots:U,refs:U,setupState:U,setupContext:null,suspense:n,suspenseId:n?n.pendingId:0,asyncDep:null,asyncResolved:!1,isMounted:!1,isUnmounted:!1,isDeactivated:!1,bc:null,c:null,bm:null,m:null,bu:null,u:null,um:null,bum:null,da:null,a:null,rtg:null,rtc:null,ec:null,sp:null};return i.ctx={_:i},i.root=t?t.root:i,i.emit=Mr.bind(null,i),e.ce&&e.ce(i),i}let ce=null,Ht,Nn;{const e=Bc(),t=(n,c)=>{let a;return(a=e[n])||(a=e[n]=[]),a.push(c),i=>{a.length>1?a.forEach(r=>r(i)):a[0](i)}};Ht=t("__VUE_INSTANCE_SETTERS__",n=>ce=n),Nn=t("__VUE_SSR_SETTERS__",n=>en=n)}const Xt=e=>{const t=ce;return Ht(e),e.scope.on(),()=>{e.scope.off(),Ht(t)}},Vc=()=>{ce&&ce.scope.off(),Ht(null)};function Ka(e){return e.vnode.shapeFlag&4}let en=!1;function Yr(e,t=!1,n=!1){t&&Nn(t);const{props:c,children:a}=e.vnode,i=Ka(e);vr(e,c,i,t),Xr(e,a,n);const r=i?Qr(e,t):void 0;return t&&Nn(!1),r}function Qr(e,t){const n=e.type;e.accessCache=Object.create(null),e.proxy=new Proxy(e.ctx,fr);const{setup:c}=n;if(c){const a=e.setupContext=c.length>1?to(e):null,i=Xt(e);Fe();const r=Oe(c,e,0,[e.props,a]);if(Le(),i(),Lc(r)){if(r.then(Vc,Vc),t)return r.then(s=>{_c(e,s,t)}).catch(s=>{Gt(s,e,0)});e.asyncDep=r}else _c(e,r,t)}else Ua(e,t)}function _c(e,t,n){x(t)?e.type.__ssrInlineRender?e.ssrRender=t:e.render=t:z(t)&&(e.setupState=ua(t)),Ua(e,n)}let yc;function Ua(e,t,n){const c=e.type;if(!e.render){if(!t&&yc&&!c.render){const a=c.template||Un(e).template;if(a){const{isCustomElement:i,compilerOptions:r}=e.appContext.config,{delimiters:s,compilerOptions:f}=c,b=ae(ae({isCustomElement:i,delimiters:s},r),f);c.render=yc(a,b)}}e.render=c.render||he}{const a=Xt(e);Fe();try{lr(e)}finally{Le(),a()}}}const eo={get(e,t){return de(e,"get",""),e[t]}};function to(e){const t=n=>{e.exposed=n||{}};return{attrs:new Proxy(e.attrs,eo),slots:e.slots,emit:e.emit,expose:t}}function Gn(e){return e.exposed?e.exposeProxy||(e.exposeProxy=new Proxy(ua($n(e.exposed)),{get(t,n){if(n in t)return t[n];if(n in ht)return ht[n](e)},has(t,n){return n in t||n in ht}})):e.proxy}function no(e){return x(e)&&"__vccOpts"in e}const za=(e,t)=>Fi(e,t,en),co="3.4.35";/**
* @vue/runtime-dom v3.4.35
* (c) 2018-present Yuxi (Evan) You and Vue contributors
* @license MIT
**/const ao="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg",io="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML",je=typeof document<"u"?document:null,Xc=je&&je.createElement("template"),ro={insert:(e,t,n)=>{t.insertBefore(e,n||null)},remove:e=>{const t=e.parentNode;t&&t.removeChild(e)},createElement:(e,t,n,c)=>{const a=t==="svg"?je.createElementNS(ao,e):t==="mathml"?je.createElementNS(io,e):n?je.createElement(e,{is:n}):je.createElement(e);return e==="select"&&c&&c.multiple!=null&&a.setAttribute("multiple",c.multiple),a},createText:e=>je.createTextNode(e),createComment:e=>je.createComment(e),setText:(e,t)=>{e.nodeValue=t},setElementText:(e,t)=>{e.textContent=t},parentNode:e=>e.parentNode,nextSibling:e=>e.nextSibling,querySelector:e=>je.querySelector(e),setScopeId(e,t){e.setAttribute(t,"")},insertStaticContent(e,t,n,c,a,i){const r=n?n.previousSibling:t.lastChild;if(a&&(a===i||a.nextSibling))for(;t.insertBefore(a.cloneNode(!0),n),!(a===i||!(a=a.nextSibling)););else{Xc.innerHTML=c==="svg"?`<svg>${e}</svg>`:c==="mathml"?`<math>${e}</math>`:e;const s=Xc.content;if(c==="svg"||c==="mathml"){const f=s.firstChild;for(;f.firstChild;)s.appendChild(f.firstChild);s.removeChild(f)}t.insertBefore(s,n)}return[r?r.nextSibling:t.firstChild,n?n.previousSibling:t.lastChild]}},oo=Symbol("_vtc");function so(e,t,n){const c=e[oo];c&&(t=(t?[t,...c]:[...c]).join(" ")),t==null?e.removeAttribute("class"):n?e.setAttribute("class",t):e.className=t}const jc=Symbol("_vod"),fo=Symbol("_vsh"),lo=Symbol(""),bo=/(^|;)\s*display\s*:/;function uo(e,t,n){const c=e.style,a=te(n);let i=!1;if(n&&!a){if(t)if(te(t))for(const r of t.split(";")){const s=r.slice(0,r.indexOf(":")).trim();n[s]==null&&Ft(c,s,"")}else for(const r in t)n[r]==null&&Ft(c,r,"");for(const r in n)r==="display"&&(i=!0),Ft(c,r,n[r])}else if(a){if(t!==n){const r=c[lo];r&&(n+=";"+r),c.cssText=n,i=bo.test(n)}}else t&&e.removeAttribute("style");jc in e&&(e[jc]=i?c.display:"",e[fo]&&(c.display="none"))}const wc=/\s*!important$/;function Ft(e,t,n){if(w(n))n.forEach(c=>Ft(e,t,c));else if(n==null&&(n=""),t.startsWith("--"))e.setProperty(t,n);else{const c=po(e,t);wc.test(n)?e.setProperty(Je(c),n.replace(wc,""),"important"):e[c]=n}}const Nc=["Webkit","Moz","ms"],bn={};function po(e,t){const n=bn[t];if(n)return n;let c=Ge(t);if(c!=="filter"&&c in e)return bn[t]=c;c=Hc(c);for(let a=0;a<Nc.length;a++){const i=Nc[a]+c;if(i in e)return bn[t]=i}return t}const Ac="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink";function xc(e,t,n,c,a,i=pi(t)){c&&t.startsWith("xlink:")?n==null?e.removeAttributeNS(Ac,t.slice(6,t.length)):e.setAttributeNS(Ac,t,n):n==null||i&&!Kc(n)?e.removeAttribute(t):e.setAttribute(t,i?"":Re(n)?String(n):n)}function ho(e,t,n,c){if(t==="innerHTML"||t==="textContent"){if(n==null)return;e[t]=n;return}const a=e.tagName;if(t==="value"&&a!=="PROGRESS"&&!a.includes("-")){const r=a==="OPTION"?e.getAttribute("value")||"":e.value,s=n==null?"":String(n);(r!==s||!("_value"in e))&&(e.value=s),n==null&&e.removeAttribute(t),e._value=n;return}let i=!1;if(n===""||n==null){const r=typeof e[t];r==="boolean"?n=Kc(n):n==null&&r==="string"?(n="",i=!0):r==="number"&&(n=0,i=!0)}try{e[t]=n}catch{}i&&e.removeAttribute(t)}function mo(e,t,n,c){e.addEventListener(t,n,c)}function Io(e,t,n,c){e.removeEventListener(t,n,c)}const Cc=Symbol("_vei");function go(e,t,n,c,a=null){const i=e[Cc]||(e[Cc]={}),r=i[t];if(c&&r)r.value=c;else{const[s,f]=ko(t);if(c){const b=i[t]=_o(c,a);mo(e,s,b,f)}else r&&(Io(e,s,r,f),i[t]=void 0)}}const Sc=/(?:Once|Passive|Capture)$/;function ko(e){let t;if(Sc.test(e)){t={};let c;for(;c=e.match(Sc);)e=e.slice(0,e.length-c[0].length),t[c[0].toLowerCase()]=!0}return[e[2]===":"?e.slice(3):Je(e.slice(2)),t]}let un=0;const vo=Promise.resolve(),Vo=()=>un||(vo.then(()=>un=0),un=Date.now());function _o(e,t){const n=c=>{if(!c._vts)c._vts=Date.now();else if(c._vts<=n.attached)return;Ie(yo(c,n.value),t,5,[c])};return n.value=e,n.attached=Vo(),n}function yo(e,t){if(w(t)){const n=e.stopImmediatePropagation;return e.stopImmediatePropagation=()=>{n.call(e),e._stopped=!0},t.map(c=>a=>!a._stopped&&c&&c(a))}else return t}const Pc=e=>e.charCodeAt(0)===111&&e.charCodeAt(1)===110&&e.charCodeAt(2)>96&&e.charCodeAt(2)<123,Xo=(e,t,n,c,a,i)=>{const r=a==="svg";t==="class"?so(e,c,r):t==="style"?uo(e,n,c):Dt(t)?Sn(t)||go(e,t,n,c,i):(t[0]==="."?(t=t.slice(1),!0):t[0]==="^"?(t=t.slice(1),!1):jo(e,t,c,r))?(ho(e,t,c),!e.tagName.includes("-")&&(t==="value"||t==="checked"||t==="selected")&&xc(e,t,c,r,i,t!=="value")):(t==="true-value"?e._trueValue=c:t==="false-value"&&(e._falseValue=c),xc(e,t,c,r))};function jo(e,t,n,c){if(c)return!!(t==="innerHTML"||t==="textContent"||t in e&&Pc(t)&&x(n));if(t==="spellcheck"||t==="draggable"||t==="translate"||t==="form"||t==="list"&&e.tagName==="INPUT"||t==="type"&&e.tagName==="TEXTAREA")return!1;if(t==="width"||t==="height"){const a=e.tagName;if(a==="IMG"||a==="VIDEO"||a==="CANVAS"||a==="SOURCE")return!1}return Pc(t)&&te(n)?!1:t in e}const wo=["ctrl","shift","alt","meta"],No={stop:e=>e.stopPropagation(),prevent:e=>e.preventDefault(),self:e=>e.target!==e.currentTarget,ctrl:e=>!e.ctrlKey,shift:e=>!e.shiftKey,alt:e=>!e.altKey,meta:e=>!e.metaKey,left:e=>"button"in e&&e.button!==0,middle:e=>"button"in e&&e.button!==1,right:e=>"button"in e&&e.button!==2,exact:(e,t)=>wo.some(n=>e[`${n}Key`]&&!t.includes(n))},Ao=(e,t)=>{const n=e._withMods||(e._withMods={}),c=t.join(".");return n[c]||(n[c]=(a,...i)=>{for(let r=0;r<t.length;r++){const s=No[t[r]];if(s&&s(a,t))return}return e(a,...i)})},xo=ae({patchProp:Xo},ro);let Ec;function Co(){return Ec||(Ec=Ar(xo))}const So=(...e)=>{const t=Co().createApp(...e),{mount:n}=t;return t.mount=c=>{const a=Eo(c);if(!a)return;const i=t._component;!x(i)&&!i.render&&!i.template&&(i.template=a.innerHTML),a.innerHTML="";const r=n(a,!1,Po(a));return a instanceof Element&&(a.removeAttribute("v-cloak"),a.setAttribute("data-v-app","")),r},t};function Po(e){if(e instanceof SVGElement)return"svg";if(typeof MathMLElement=="function"&&e instanceof MathMLElement)return"mathml"}function Eo(e){return te(e)?document.querySelector(e):e}var Oo=!1;/*!
 * pinia v2.2.0
 * (c) 2024 Eduardo San Martin Morote
 * @license MIT
 */let Wa;const tn=e=>Wa=e,Ga=Symbol();function An(e){return e&&typeof e=="object"&&Object.prototype.toString.call(e)==="[object Object]"&&typeof e.toJSON!="function"}var gt;(function(e){e.direct="direct",e.patchObject="patch object",e.patchFunction="patch function"})(gt||(gt={}));function To(){const e=Gc(!0),t=e.run(()=>nt({}));let n=[],c=[];const a=$n({install(i){tn(a),a._a=i,i.provide(Ga,a),i.config.globalProperties.$pinia=a,c.forEach(r=>n.push(r)),c=[]},use(i){return!this._a&&!Oo?c.push(i):n.push(i),this},_p:n,_a:null,_e:e,_s:new Map,state:t});return a}const Za=()=>{};function Oc(e,t,n,c=Za){e.push(t);const a=()=>{const i=e.indexOf(t);i>-1&&(e.splice(i,1),c())};return!n&&Zc()&&mi(a),a}function Qe(e,...t){e.slice().forEach(n=>{n(...t)})}const Mo=e=>e(),Tc=Symbol(),pn=Symbol();function xn(e,t){e instanceof Map&&t instanceof Map?t.forEach((n,c)=>e.set(c,n)):e instanceof Set&&t instanceof Set&&t.forEach(e.add,e);for(const n in t){if(!t.hasOwnProperty(n))continue;const c=t[n],a=e[n];An(a)&&An(c)&&e.hasOwnProperty(n)&&!Q(c)&&!We(c)?e[n]=xn(a,c):e[n]=c}return e}const Ro=Symbol();function Fo(e){return!An(e)||!e.hasOwnProperty(Ro)}const{assign:Ce}=Object;function Lo(e){return!!(Q(e)&&e.effect)}function qo(e,t,n,c){const{state:a,actions:i,getters:r}=t,s=n.state.value[e];let f;function b(){s||(n.state.value[e]=a?a():{});const l=Hi(n.state.value[e]);return Ce(l,i,Object.keys(r||{}).reduce((g,y)=>(g[y]=$n(za(()=>{tn(n);const A=n._s.get(e);return r[y].call(A,A)})),g),{}))}return f=Ja(e,b,t,n,c,!0),f}function Ja(e,t,n={},c,a,i){let r;const s=Ce({actions:{}},n),f={deep:!0};let b,l,g=[],y=[],A;const L=c.state.value[e];!i&&!L&&(c.state.value[e]={}),nt({});let E;function Y(S){let F;b=l=!1,typeof S=="function"?(S(c.state.value[e]),F={type:gt.patchFunction,storeId:e,events:A}):(xn(c.state.value[e],S),F={type:gt.patchObject,payload:S,storeId:e,events:A});const J=E=Symbol();ha().then(()=>{E===J&&(b=!0)}),l=!0,Qe(g,F,c.state.value[e])}const B=i?function(){const{state:F}=n,J=F?F():{};this.$patch(ue=>{Ce(ue,J)})}:Za;function W(){r.stop(),g=[],y=[],c._s.delete(e)}const T=(S,F="")=>{if(Tc in S)return S[pn]=F,S;const J=function(){tn(c);const ue=Array.from(arguments),ke=[],Ae=[];function ot(P){ke.push(P)}function jt(P){Ae.push(P)}Qe(y,{args:ue,name:J[pn],store:K,after:ot,onError:jt});let G;try{G=S.apply(this&&this.$id===e?this:K,ue)}catch(P){throw Qe(Ae,P),P}return G instanceof Promise?G.then(P=>(Qe(ke,P),P)).catch(P=>(Qe(Ae,P),Promise.reject(P))):(Qe(ke,G),G)};return J[Tc]=!0,J[pn]=F,J},Z={_p:c,$id:e,$onAction:Oc.bind(null,y),$patch:Y,$reset:B,$subscribe(S,F={}){const J=Oc(g,S,F.detached,()=>ue()),ue=r.run(()=>Mt(()=>c.state.value[e],ke=>{(F.flush==="sync"?l:b)&&S({storeId:e,type:gt.direct,events:A},ke)},Ce({},f,F)));return J},$dispose:W},K=Wt(Z);c._s.set(e,K);const ie=(c._a&&c._a.runWithContext||Mo)(()=>c._e.run(()=>(r=Gc()).run(()=>t({action:T}))));for(const S in ie){const F=ie[S];if(Q(F)&&!Lo(F)||We(F))i||(L&&Fo(F)&&(Q(F)?F.value=L[S]:xn(F,L[S])),c.state.value[e][S]=F);else if(typeof F=="function"){const J=T(F,S);ie[S]=J,s.actions[S]=F}}return Ce(K,ie),Ce(R(K),ie),Object.defineProperty(K,"$state",{get:()=>c.state.value[e],set:S=>{Y(F=>{Ce(F,S)})}}),c._p.forEach(S=>{Ce(K,r.run(()=>S({store:K,app:c._a,pinia:c,options:s})))}),L&&i&&n.hydrate&&n.hydrate(K.$state,L),b=!0,l=!0,K}function $o(e,t,n){let c,a;const i=typeof t=="function";c=e,a=i?n:t;function r(s,f){const b=kr();return s=s||(b?mt(Ga,null):null),s&&tn(s),s=Wa,s._s.has(c)||(i?Ja(c,t,a,s):qo(c,a,s)),s._s.get(c)}return r.$id=c,r}const nn=e=>(Zi("data-v-f6b8e857"),e=e(),Ji(),e),Ho={class:"flip-card"},Do={key:0,class:"no-more-cards"},Bo={class:"flip-card-back"},Ko={class:"button-container"},Uo=nn(()=>$("svg",{xmlns:"http://www.w3.org/2000/svg",viewBox:"0 0  32 32",fill:"currentColor"},[$("path",{d:"m 18,18 a 1,1 0 0 0 -1,1 v 3 a 1,1 0 0 0 1,1 1,1 0 0 0 1,-1 V 19 A 1,1 0 0 0 18,18 Z M 16,2 C 8.2629707,2 2,8.2629707 2,16 c 0,7.737029 6.2629707,14 14,14 1.948146,0 3.771489,-0.432424 5.371094,-1.072266 a 1,1 0 0 0 0.55664,-1.298828 1,1 0 0 0 -1.298828,-0.55664 C 19.228514,27.632422 17.65185,28 16,28 9.3370437,28 4,22.662956 4,16 4,9.3370437 9.3370437,4 16,4 c 6.662956,0 12,5.3370437 12,12 0,0.866666 -0.18086,1.804688 -0.380859,2.804687 a 1,1 0 0 0 0.785156,1.175782 1,1 0 0 0 1.175781,-0.785157 C 29.780078,18.195313 30,17.133332 30,16 30,8.2629707 23.737029,2 16,2 Z m 6,12 c -1.266665,0 -2.395172,0.507525 -3.25,1.240234 a 1,1 0 0 0 -0.109375,1.410157 1,1 0 0 0 1.410156,0.109375 C 20.595952,16.292476 21.266667,16 22,16 c 0.733333,0 1.404048,0.292476 1.949219,0.759766 A 1,1 0 0 0 25.359375,16.650391 1,1 0 0 0 25.25,15.240234 C 24.395172,14.507525 23.266665,14 22,14 Z m -9,0 c -1.266665,0 -2.395172,0.507525 -3.25,1.240234 a 1,1 0 0 0 -0.109375,1.410157 1,1 0 0 0 1.410156,0.109375 C 11.595952,16.292476 12.266667,16 13,16 c 0.733333,0 1.404048,0.292476 1.949219,0.759766 A 1,1 0 0 0 16.359375,16.650391 1,1 0 0 0 16.25,15.240234 C 15.395172,14.507525 14.266665,14 13,14 Z m 9.75,6.089844 c -0.710955,0 -1.421837,0.26754 -1.957031,0.802734 -1.10406,1.10406 -1.07126,2.893449 -0.04492,4.066406 a 1.0001,1.0001 0 0 0 0.01172,0.01367 l 1,1.09961 a 1.0001,1.0001 0 0 0 0.01953,0.02148 l 2.5,2.599609 a 1.0001,1.0001 0 0 0 1.455078,-0.01367 l 2.5,-2.701171 a 1.0001,1.0001 0 0 0 0.0059,-0.0059 l 1,-1.099609 -0.0332,0.0332 c 1.10406,-1.10406 1.10406,-2.909612 0,-4.013672 -1.070388,-1.070388 -2.843674,-1.070388 -3.914062,0 a 1.0001,1.0001 0 0 0 -0.0332,0.03516 L 25,21.212891 24.740234,20.927734 a 1.0001,1.0001 0 0 0 -0.0332,-0.03516 C 24.171837,20.357384 23.460955,20.089844 22.75,20.089844 Z m -0.542969,2.216797 c 0.328425,-0.328425 0.752914,-0.326062 1.082031,0 l 0.970704,1.066406 a 1.0001,1.0001 0 0 0 1.480468,0 l 0.970703,-1.066406 c 0.329118,-0.326062 0.753607,-0.328425 1.082032,0 0.295938,0.295938 0.295938,0.889608 0,1.185546 a 1.0001,1.0001 0 0 0 -0.0332,0.03516 L 26.763675,24.62305 24.986331,26.542972 23.230472,24.7168 22.251956,23.640628 v -0.002 c -0.372249,-0.426971 -0.340508,-1.036445 -0.04492,-1.332031 z"})],-1)),zo=[Uo],Wo=nn(()=>$("svg",{xmlns:"http://www.w3.org/2000/svg",viewBox:"0 0  32 32",fill:"currentColor"},[$("path",{d:"m 20,11 a 1,1 0 0 0 -1,1 v 4 a 1,1 0 0 0 1,1 1,1 0 0 0 1,-1 v -4 a 1,1 0 0 0 -1,-1 z m -8,0 a 1,1 0 0 0 -1,1 v 4 a 1,1 0 0 0 1,1 1,1 0 0 0 1,-1 v -4 a 1,1 0 0 0 -1,-1 z m -1.376953,7.003906 a 1,1 0 0 0 -0.6816407,0.345703 1,1 0 0 0 0.1074217,1.410157 C 11.62152,21.107787 13.733336,22 16,22 c 2.266664,0 4.37848,-0.892213 5.951172,-2.240234 a 1,1 0 0 0 0.107422,-1.410157 1,1 0 0 0 -1.410157,-0.109375 C 19.421132,19.29221 17.733332,20 16,20 14.266668,20 12.578868,19.29221 11.351563,18.240234 A 1,1 0 0 0 10.623047,18.003906 Z M 16,2 C 8.2798659,2 2,8.2798659 2,16 2,23.720134 8.2798659,30 16,30 23.720134,30 30,23.720134 30,16 30,8.2798659 23.720134,2 16,2 Z m 0,2 C 22.639255,4 28,9.360745 28,16 28,22.639255 22.639255,28 16,28 9.360745,28 4,22.639255 4,16 4,9.360745 9.360745,4 16,4 Z"})],-1)),Go=[Wo],Zo=nn(()=>$("svg",{xmlns:"http://www.w3.org/2000/svg",viewBox:"0 0  32 32",fill:"currentColor"},[$("path",{d:"M 16,2 C 8.2798659,2 2,8.2798659 2,16 2,23.720134 8.2798659,30 16,30 23.720134,30 30,23.720134 30,16 30,8.2798659 23.720134,2 16,2 Z m 0,2 C 22.639255,4 28,9.360745 28,16 28,22.639255 22.639255,28 16,28 9.360745,28 4,22.639255 4,16 4,9.360745 9.360745,4 16,4 Z m -4,7 a 1,1 0 0 0 -1,1 v 4 a 1,1 0 0 0 1,1 1,1 0 0 0 1,-1 v -4 a 1,1 0 0 0 -1,-1 z m 8,0 a 1,1 0 0 0 -1,1 v 4 a 1,1 0 0 0 1,1 1,1 0 0 0 1,-1 v -4 a 1,1 0 0 0 -1,-1 z m -10,8 a 1,1 0 0 0 -1,1 1,1 0 0 0 1,1 h 12 a 1,1 0 0 0 1,-1 1,1 0 0 0 -1,-1 z"})],-1)),Jo=[Zo],Yo=nn(()=>$("svg",{xmlns:"http://www.w3.org/2000/svg",viewBox:"0 0  32 32",fill:"currentColor"},[$("path",{d:"M 16,2 C 8.2798659,2 2,8.2798659 2,16 2,23.720134 8.2798659,30 16,30 23.720134,30 30,23.720134 30,16 30,8.2798659 23.720134,2 16,2 Z m 0,2 C 22.639255,4 28,9.360745 28,16 28,22.639255 22.639255,28 16,28 9.360745,28 4,22.639255 4,16 4,9.360745 9.360745,4 16,4 Z m -7.8066406,8.193359 a 1,1 0 0 0 0,1.414063 L 9.5859375,15 8.1933594,16.392578 a 1,1 0 0 0 0,1.414063 1,1 0 0 0 1.4140625,0 L 11,16.414062 l 1.392578,1.392579 a 1,1 0 0 0 1.414063,0 1,1 0 0 0 0,-1.414063 L 12.414063,15 13.806641,13.607422 a 1,1 0 0 0 0,-1.414063 1,1 0 0 0 -1.414063,0 L 11,13.585938 9.6074219,12.193359 a 1,1 0 0 0 -1.4140625,0 z m 9.9999996,0 a 1,1 0 0 0 0,1.414063 L 19.585937,15 18.193359,16.392578 a 1,1 0 0 0 0,1.414063 1,1 0 0 0 1.414063,0 L 21,16.414062 l 1.392578,1.392579 a 1,1 0 0 0 1.414063,0 1,1 0 0 0 0,-1.414063 L 22.414062,15 23.806641,13.607422 a 1,1 0 0 0 0,-1.414063 1,1 0 0 0 -1.414063,0 L 21,13.585938 19.607422,12.193359 a 1,1 0 0 0 -1.414063,0 z M 16,18.474609 c -1.436477,0 -2.872751,0.18712 -4.259766,0.560547 a 1,1 0 0 0 -0.705078,1.22461 1,1 0 0 0 1.22461,0.705078 c 2.425964,-0.653145 5.054504,-0.653145 7.480468,0 a 1,1 0 0 0 1.22461,-0.705078 1,1 0 0 0 -0.705078,-1.22461 C 18.872751,18.661729 17.436477,18.474609 16,18.474609 Z"})],-1)),Qo=[Yo],es=va({__name:"FlipCard",props:{canFlip:Boolean},emits:["buttonClicked","flipped"],setup(e,{emit:t}){const n=nt(!1),c=e,a=t;let i;const r=()=>{c.canFlip&&(n.value=!n.value)},s=b=>{i=b,a("buttonClicked",i),i=void 0,r()},f=b=>{b.target&&b.target instanceof HTMLElement&&b.target.className.indexOf("flip-card-inner")===-1||a("flipped",n.value?"back":"front")};return Kn(()=>{document.querySelector(".flip-card-inner").addEventListener("transitionend",f)}),(b,l)=>(_t(),wn("div",Ho,[$("div",{class:Ut(["flip-card-inner",{flipped:n.value}])},[$("div",{class:"flip-card-front",onClick:r},[bc(b.$slots,"front",{},void 0),e.canFlip?zr("",!0):(_t(),wn("h1",Do,"No more cards!"))]),$("div",Bo,[bc(b.$slots,"back",{},void 0),$("div",Ko,[$("div",{class:"circle-button easy-button",onClick:l[0]||(l[0]=Ao(g=>s("easy"),["stop"]))},zo),$("div",{class:"circle-button good-button",onClick:l[1]||(l[1]=g=>s("good"))},Go),$("div",{class:"circle-button hard-button",onClick:l[2]||(l[2]=g=>s("hard"))},Jo),$("div",{class:"circle-button again-button",onClick:l[3]||(l[3]=g=>s("again"))},Qo)])])],2)]))}}),ts=(e,t)=>{const n=e.__vccOpts||e;for(const[c,a]of t)n[c]=a;return n},ns=ts(es,[["__scopeId","data-v-f6b8e857"]]),cs=[{id:"485544f1-07e7-45ee-9a35-a42212d8d2a7",front:"capitulum, -ī",back:"chapter",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"6ccf92c5-fd53-49db-8ef8-dcaf39e04772",front:"exemplum, -ī",back:"example, model",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"81eb4008-013e-49a5-937c-31b5f1f4a5c5",front:"fluvius, -ī",back:"river",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"0637b3cc-e467-42c0-a7e9-dee20c63f2a1",front:"grammatica, -ae",back:"grammar",description:"Noun, f., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"277fd888-0baa-4a4f-b9c2-f043860f387e",front:"imperium, -ī",back:"command, empire",description:"Noun, n., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"d8e461ef-077c-4642-90d2-3d2887f2b4b7",front:"īnsula, -ae",back:"island",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"e28e2869-51a3-4c26-a3be-ed202b8afeb3",front:"littera, -ae",back:"letter",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"96c3e6c9-4694-4de8-98f5-211064a489f3",front:"numerus, -ī",back:"number",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"c98185ee-5cac-4d14-ab9e-7ab81bd604c6",front:"ōceanus, -ī",back:"ocean",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"7b0cc750-75be-4dbd-affa-e055907c2329",front:"oppidum, -ī",back:"town",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"932a903f-914c-4bc5-9a5a-fe2295ce939d",front:"pēnsum, -ī",back:"task",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"cb003f49-4f9b-4be3-9b2a-2653824589ed",front:"prōvincia, -ae",back:"province",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"962c6d69-2fb3-4ccd-be79-9f6e4941f765",front:"syllaba, -ae",back:"syllable",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"47462f77-2eec-469b-8721-b926a4505551",front:"vocābulum, -ī",back:"word",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"48416fc0-b2b4-40fd-ae41-4f9093c2d42b",front:"est",back:"he/she/it is",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"ce58d6c2-02ef-4032-8ab4-7e5dd70cb718",front:"sunt",back:"they are",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"e321aaf8-2ea0-418a-9e4d-a2c25a1e8ff4",front:"Graecus, -a, -um",back:"Greek",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"c55c00ff-2ef1-4ec7-b09e-a4e2aa9e38d6",front:"Latīnus, -a, -um",back:"Latin",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"0215daba-7a40-47da-84f7-fa1e2ce6078f",front:"magnus, -a, -um",back:"big, large, great",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"70e8facb-f253-47a8-b975-7636723d5d19",front:"multī, -ae, -a",back:"many, a great many",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"d6213026-cbd9-4b73-8f84-3f155c933beb",front:"parvus, -a, -um",back:"little, small",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"cc9ecf8b-3a93-45dc-a13e-064fe5200358",front:"paucī, -ae, -a",back:"few, a few",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"526e62ad-f61c-46c2-9867-bcc872fbfebf",front:"prīmus, -a, -um",back:"first",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"0f3f3a29-3e8b-4e42-b760-f5bb792038f1",front:"Rōmānus, -a, -um",back:"Roman, of Rome",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"3108e7fe-af4c-4d74-b253-44d1aa19db7b",front:"secundus, -a, -um",back:"second, favorable",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"af10febf-a16c-4b95-9458-dd2770936a49",front:"tertius, -a, -um",back:"third",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"69f8ea22-6c95-4c96-8f01-6a9f8e06eb64",front:"ūnus",back:"one, only",description:"Numeral",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"829806dc-bd6c-4d58-811b-cfaf36353b28",front:"duo",back:"two",description:"Numeral",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"28f67b5f-efff-40db-b55d-248afda7f808",front:"trēs",back:"three",description:"Numeral",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"4469d63c-afe8-4f9c-acb0-e0e3eaa33354",front:"sex",back:"six",description:"Numeral",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"9f333709-3b4f-4f80-8432-5ab1f5ed07ea",front:"mīlle",back:"one thousand",description:"Numeral",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"50218262-0ac0-41c3-872c-90f5b606ab9b",front:"nōn",back:"not",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"b95e5ba8-3c60-4ac1-b992-38e9187751ea",front:"in",back:"in, on, at",description:"Preposition + abl",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"cb71dd64-5f9c-41b6-86f0-3bd996983436",front:"in",back:"into, to, against",description:"Preposition + acc",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"ccfc5bb7-29a0-4798-be4b-f324cd77a9e3",front:"-ne?",back:"",description:"Added to the end of a word in a phrase (usually the first word) to make it a question.",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"50462015-1f84-4b09-83bc-ae25450bae4a",front:"num?",back:"if, whether",description:"Interrogative",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"e90f7736-0106-46b2-9c66-3d837e1fb161",front:"quid?",back:"what, anything",description:"Interrogative",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"e4e1d4e7-e97d-4380-9437-04934f5e791d",front:"ubi?",back:"where",description:"Interrogative",meta:{chapter:"I"}},{id:"c70cf0f2-afb2-4e3b-93d8-1525a103599f",front:"ancilla, -ae",back:"female, slave, servant",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"36fda3d8-2426-4a47-acb9-66d921b9ac33",front:"domina, -ae",back:"mistress",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"99b303d7-4b9d-46db-bde6-1d68661a24bf",front:"familia, -ae",back:"domestic staff, family",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"822ad328-1697-4bf5-a3d6-ae20ab01851a",front:"fēmina, -ae",back:"woman",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"65589ea4-8342-4c88-bd7f-4f9a64c03f7e",front:"fīlia, -ae",back:"daughter",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"7948d9f9-290e-4641-b4b2-c9ed1eec52e7",front:"dominus, -ī",back:"master",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"c999a064-cacf-4337-8591-58f31b7d9709",front:"fīlius, -ī",back:"son",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"a28971bf-361e-49a2-ad97-98b46a2e7f41",front:"liber, -brī",back:"book",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"39d42028-bec2-4ce7-bbed-ee91d61f5b2a",front:"līberī, -ōrum",back:"children",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"a01f3085-9b18-4d1f-b509-bfe32a0733fa",front:"puer, -ēri",back:"boy",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"0b75e2bf-1f2a-4048-bccb-de0744ce869d",front:"servus, -ī",back:"slave, servant",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"098ca745-0974-4898-b831-ac954677999f",front:"titulus, -ī",back:"title",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"058f8416-308a-4691-b0f5-9c2cbe351ee9",front:"vir, -ī",back:"man, husband",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"936ec899-36f0-4a54-b72e-2fc3703b0467",front:"māter",back:"mother",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"b68904de-c07e-4f26-80e8-8c28832b5d74",front:"pater",back:"father",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"a2a3687f-d064-4b08-aa03-f2bf3b5da379",front:"antīquus, -a, -um",back:"old, ancient, former",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"43f4e8ee-b83b-4ed5-a7ff-a598f92fbe03",front:"centum",back:"a hundred",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"b6f5fca8-841c-41fa-a040-6f0131934295",front:"cēterī, -ae, -a",back:"the other(s), the rest",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"f4a8c9ba-503a-4e51-b263-1cb9ef46217e",front:"duo, duae, duo",back:"two",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"ca4239dd-cddd-4552-bd3e-0a29ce816cb9",front:"meus, -a, -um",back:"my, mine",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"d1dbdcf4-f6dc-473a-a0a9-08c19300dc0e",front:"novus, -a, -um",back:"new",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"74102cc8-2307-405a-950e-45c980ab6761",front:"tuus, -a, -um",back:"your, yours",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"68634b68-77ab-41e7-bcf1-f8c19e5f61a4",front:"trēs, tria",back:"three",description:"Adjective, 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"dc205bdb-46e2-4637-a6a3-b6a4e67a0804",front:"quis?, quae? quid?",back:"who, what",description:"Pronoun (nom)",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"2dd68ae2-9882-46f0-b5dd-b89e9a8c76ec",front:"qui?",back:"what, which",description:"Pronoun (nom)",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"fb9252e6-5e67-45db-b1ec-a8eed4882b57",front:"cuius?",back:"whose",description:"Pronoun (gen)",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"12395211-482f-46fc-bf47-ef42437a9542",front:"quot?",back:"how many, (as many) as",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"1ed1ddf0-c223-4b83-a6e2-22fbdda38458",front:"-que",back:"and",description:"Conjunction",meta:{chapter:"II"}},{id:"9cdae093-4c56-4c66-a6a1-0376ce532302",front:"mamma, -ae",back:"mommy",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"b2bf1d26-eb44-4457-883f-164f9471dc71",front:"persōna, -ae",back:"character, person",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"7f2ccc37-2610-4c79-9fff-f8c51a5f5a05",front:"scaena, -ae",back:"scene, stage",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"69354117-26d1-4363-8d1b-bb92bdacb84e",front:"verbum, -ī",back:"word, verb",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"c243765b-568a-43b1-804a-ff3c4c6158d4",front:"cantat",back:"sing",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"f6a841ae-1449-4fa0-8952-e6aafad443e6",front:"interrogat",back:"ask, question",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"54f3e37b-674f-41ed-aac5-a4b4c80455c9",front:"plōrat",back:"cry",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"80ecea0b-f3d0-47d5-ac51-f01292c68f0a",front:"pulsat",back:"strike, hit, knock (at)",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"977cdb31-05c9-4902-9918-fcb2f4a82df1",front:"verberat",back:"beat, flog",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"16752228-232e-4e9a-a9e9-4b54253d88ad",front:"vocat",back:"call, invite",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"df92735e-2f1b-4a7a-b5ee-ce4b35c33b6a",front:"respondet",back:"answer",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"a8b648d8-b952-48ee-91ef-cc1e29613094",front:"rīdet",back:"laugh, make fun of",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"2e538d74-32ce-486a-a9d4-9811859a749d",front:"videt",back:"see",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"15f64305-f2cc-42d2-b7d1-3b6be9b9270a",front:"audit",back:"hear, listen",description:"Verb, 4. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"fba6a310-faab-49bb-a491-8ed030927732",front:"dormit",back:"sleep",description:"Verb, 4. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"8da0056b-70cb-4fc4-8f9a-caca26747099",front:"venit",back:"come",description:"Verb, 4. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"a7dcb1ba-de43-4640-a2c0-63179b42c80f",front:"improbus, -a, -um",back:"bad, wicked",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"feac1887-1215-4e81-a7de-57a1c0b97220",front:"īrātus, -a, -um",back:"angry",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"469a3be3-1337-45bf-b804-f91e38444719",front:"laetus, -a, -um",back:"glad, happy",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"d7899534-2d96-4f61-aa90-217061df5c78",front:"probus, -a, -um",back:"good, honest, proper",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"6df516c5-14d3-4983-b82a-d4e2ca4b3295",front:"eam",back:"her",description:"Pronoun (acc)",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"585901ba-9e01-4b37-9f6f-9a054d1f1483",front:"eum",back:"him",description:"Pronoun (acc)",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"b0205869-d18b-4777-97c7-e1713677cebd",front:"mē",back:"me",description:"Pronoun (acc/abl)",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"78160432-cb73-42b2-b116-dfe26e3a6a8a",front:"quae",back:"who, which, she wo",description:"Pronoun (acc)",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"fdae0c5f-d21f-4923-ba1d-824b842be4ac",front:"quam",back:"whom, which, she whom",description:"Pronoun (acc)",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"f7f436a2-c876-44aa-90a7-978a2ec1e2fc",front:"quem",back:"whom, which, he whom",description:"Pronoun (acc)",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"44ac2b62-b0ea-48b9-9a8c-6347a64295ed",front:"quī",back:"who, which, he who",description:"Pronoun (acc)",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"3b1c4942-4fec-43f1-ba93-a7711855e63f",front:"tē",back:"you",description:"Pronoun (acc/abl)",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"50d78274-482a-4e4c-8b5e-a844afaff0df",front:"cūr?",back:"why?",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"287c6fa0-1d2c-413a-8141-2dcb9ef5c903",front:"iam",back:"now, already",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"d254bbd2-442f-434e-aa8b-4543def165ab",front:"hīc",back:"here",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"ce223a10-6c03-4729-8214-b2365d510d11",front:"ō!",back:"oh!",description:"Etc",meta:{chapter:"III"}},{id:"52c5c18c-409e-4b91-9005-0a7c69c248a4",front:"mēnsa, -ae",back:"table",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"f88306b9-c4c3-47e4-8198-5c6a7428e584",front:"pecūnia, -ae",back:"money",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"488d0ab5-bb54-466f-98da-d371ca293241",front:"baculum, -ī",back:"stick",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"38501bbb-75bc-4edc-96c6-660c75efe822",front:"nummus, -ī",back:"coin",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"3f88cbdb-d08b-4289-94ef-d99d2e994817",front:"sacculus, -ī",back:"purse",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"3fdc0942-1c52-48c1-b640-607c266248f6",front:"accūsat",back:"accuse",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"249b8905-1a4d-482f-909d-a2aca8ef560e",front:"imperat",back:"command, order, rule",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"6756b324-ee6f-4d2e-8198-1cbbd40325b0",front:"numerat",back:"count",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"ee8d815b-1919-4161-ac38-6daad777d525",front:"salūtat",back:"greet",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"c1b21bec-ccbe-4061-b389-9f3c4ad7735c",front:"habet",back:"have, hold, consider",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"ebe047b2-b8d6-4698-88e2-f209ee2b7193",front:"pāret",back:"obey",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"748a7799-4c61-44f3-9a28-70070ba4de42",front:"tacet",back:"be silent",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"425cbd9e-6ca0-4092-9e0a-aaf426f1d58a",front:"discēdit",back:"go away, depart",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"d00401fe-0cbd-4716-bda3-b03b337b13ef",front:"pōnit",back:"place, put, lay down",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"fe9ce4c6-09c5-4df4-b992-5bf76181a1d3",front:"sūmit",back:"take",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"e8100c88-f8a8-42b9-9e65-c06cfab92ed9",front:"abest",back:"be absent",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"2d2e6dea-b1c4-45db-b7d9-74f6c0d9f0a7",front:"adest",back:"be present",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"66bcf9ff-eb74-446b-973b-c5fe1be4225a",front:"bonus, -a, -um",back:"good",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"f2aa00d9-3e70-43f2-a6f2-13886afa5c01",front:"decem",back:"ten",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"770638c7-f830-4e93-8803-0e69a36db443",front:"novem",back:"nine",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"a204010c-78cb-4e42-a8da-323c5ae702f5",front:"nūllus, -a, -um",back:"no, none",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"8111587f-7cf7-4ff1-85da-058b021f0fe4",front:"octō",back:"eight",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"060ba42e-0cbc-472f-b223-c68899117713",front:"quattuor",back:"four",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"adc65086-a81c-437d-af84-f57ec30cd2a2",front:"quīnque",back:"five",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"93eeeabf-7c35-4b42-bd48-82aa4c1f4801",front:"septem",back:"seven",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"d8d96329-b580-4a00-874e-5d1c1e6df3f9",front:"suus, -a, -um",back:"his, her, their (own)",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"d985001b-c3e6-4126-b7e2-1832a419e8e5",front:"vacuus, -a, -um",back:"empty",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"e40bf03d-6330-40d7-b31b-db71a576115f",front:"eius",back:"his",description:"Pronoun (gen)",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"08423800-a3c4-4e83-a7f0-0c89a8e37727",front:"is, ea, id",back:"he, she, it, that",description:"Pronoun (nom)",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"bc424415-ae69-428f-ab7b-3b44284ffea6",front:"quī, quae, quod",back:"who, which, that",description:"Pronoun (nom)",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"5896b707-09e2-43a6-a16f-23ee143f03e7",front:"rūrsum",back:"again, back",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"df29e5b6-2fa5-4c4a-b3d6-cbcc6cc24f2a",front:"tantum",back:"so much, only",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"a21d4c93-aabe-4eb3-9e69-c89af2e23e2e",front:"salvē!",back:"hello, good morning",description:"Interjection",meta:{chapter:"IV"}},{id:"488dd52f-e5b8-4caa-8f7b-523876419d11",front:"aqua, -ae",back:"water",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"be0164e5-f0bb-49a7-85f3-42fb41798fe9",front:"fenestra, -ae",back:"window",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"d354ceb6-9bea-488a-9575-b2b9d1b13022",front:"rosa, -ae",back:"rose",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"5d18b05d-2c69-40b7-8876-e68c4ea70438",front:"vīlla, -ae",back:"country house, villa",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"7b43f95c-5e61-43b7-9d0d-9e1cc8b3f500",front:"ātrium, -ī",back:"main room, hall",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"e5ddc5b8-6060-4143-9ab7-7c21fa23163a",front:"cubiculum, -ī",back:"bedroom",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"ebcb4984-e90b-43ca-8d39-d00f723dc530",front:"hortus, -ī",back:"garden",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"96d6a07c-08d0-496d-a0bd-3dec4f53d0f2",front:"impluvium, -ī",back:"water basin in the atrium for collecting rainwater",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"7bf91297-1192-4655-b13a-98a129371bfb",front:"līlium, -ī",back:"lily",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"40147b54-17f7-4c5a-82af-5a459fd3162f",front:"nāsus, -ī",back:"nose",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"1d39ad87-956d-4322-99a2-a0638ab53efd",front:"ōstium, -ī",back:"door, entrance",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"6129a6a8-5440-482c-9fb7-45ed863158e1",front:"peristȳlum, -ī",back:"peristyle",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"a46d8a0a-2bb8-408e-957d-93bdc4241353",front:"amat, amant",back:"love",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"22cbd5e2-0f44-4cd5-a30b-7aca3e9439c1",front:"dēlectat, dēlectant",back:"delight, please",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"61ce4467-f4c3-475f-97ff-7a18e64bf115",front:"habitat, habitant",back:"dwell, live",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"886fb216-0f26-41c3-9ef7-1d730a60b7d3",front:"agit, agunt",back:"drive, do, perform",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"327ad460-2f9a-4d91-babd-aa122328f4a4",front:"carpit, carpunt",back:"gather, pick, crop",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"60e3fa26-a9d5-4b69-8874-3d2c9dfc2ac2",front:"foedus, -a, -um",back:"ugly, hideous",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"05582568-94f7-4cb8-8fdb-79d1499b0ae1",front:"pulcher, -chra, -chrum",back:"beautiful, fine",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"4e308b2d-9149-4f97-869b-bf124cbd5217",front:"sōlus, -a, -um",back:"alone, lonely",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"9dc83886-2388-4397-831e-423f186f5511",front:"is, ea, id",back:"he, she, it",description:"Pronoun (nom)",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"b82a18f9-c434-48e1-b8e0-260e215a661b",front:"etiam",back:"also, even, yet",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"1abec260-d178-4fa9-b2ea-975945f48869",front:"ab",back:"from, by",description:"Preposition + abl",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"a8709170-5062-42a9-9a2b-641aa58c1128",front:"cum",back:"with",description:"Preposition + abl",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"7888a140-df16-4ffe-996c-b0afc2c80ddb",front:"ex",back:"out of, by",description:"Preposition + abl",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"3be62b19-6a88-4d8a-a82a-50e3a2ee1e1b",front:"sine",back:"without",description:"Preposition + abl",meta:{chapter:"V"}},{id:"48dad843-1401-4eb2-8255-008d3f7c382f",front:"amīca, -ae",back:"female friend",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"28d75f7f-f222-4443-a43f-37083badfa29",front:"lectīca, -ae",back:"litter, sedan",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"45d123af-9d44-4296-af5f-1ae402801ee3",front:"porta, -ae",back:"gate",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"e1ce5b17-4f53-4f87-9867-c3331096b2ab",front:"via, -ae",back:"road, way, street",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"23e485d6-2dee-4cda-b8fd-9b9abd022292",front:"amīcus, -ī",back:"friend",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"a685a205-6a2e-4bd1-8975-e82aa4350992",front:"equus, -ī",back:"horse",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"03ea5218-4329-4b2f-8e1c-9e0982549864",front:"inimīcus, -ī",back:"(personal) enemy",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"ecc74a98-46e2-48c8-b064-15c96adf1163",front:"mūrus, -i",back:"wall",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"3f1eacc9-a0a6-42db-8cf9-2df7f7f32739",front:"saccus, -ī",back:"sack",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"1230b745-2913-4bf3-a82c-5d0c6fa1af8d",front:"umerus, -ī",back:"shoulder",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"818ceabb-69af-4222-b23e-fe69fe635dfb",front:"praepositiō",back:"preposition",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"ff591cd8-0edc-4f53-9ed9-ff8352a27ae4",front:"ambulat, ambulant",back:"walk",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"663a19be-5846-4cca-9651-4746ef6d1f77",front:"intrat, intrant",back:"enter",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"df152287-179c-4dfe-b147-22d907dcb286",front:"portat, portant",back:"carry",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"b36e2fe6-a2c1-47e4-b089-cd0f7e5a0e24",front:"timet, timent",back:"fear, be afraid (of)",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"93b0ff17-589a-4be4-910e-14a35ac9ab39",front:"vehit, vehunt",back:"carry, convey, ride, sail, travel",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"d27c3d33-5288-4039-a061-3b99018c380d",front:"it, eunt",back:"go",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"22319b16-8a91-478b-9e76-5da4f750f114",front:"duodecim",back:"twelve",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"2cbb4d69-aba5-4f25-931b-dee49f6f4bac",front:"fessus, -a, -um",back:"tired, weary",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"0fe98fcb-062d-4993-ba6d-4254211f96a0",front:"longus, -a, -um",back:"long",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"680c3a0e-b02b-460d-8e4c-6a742dbcf77a",front:"malus, -a, -um",back:"bad, wicked, evil",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"a89a86d7-8696-49f3-a979-b1195102b1f1",front:"ante",back:"in front of, before",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"9de8540d-aa27-4bea-8f00-d9e553912e01",front:"autem",back:"but, however",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"10e6246c-9516-41b2-9eec-4ebde3449ec2",front:"itaque",back:"therefore",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"de311990-0cb9-49cc-803c-da3751e2f07e",front:"nam",back:"for",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"42ecc29f-7ec6-47c7-8f26-6c7dc582e5a0",front:"procul",back:"far",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"22baaec6-f00e-4b1f-9ba6-07b5708e7e4e",front:"quam",back:"how, as, than",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"a7a057ec-f17f-46f9-81ee-cb644b4508e9",front:"tam",back:"so, as",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"efc251c2-10e8-4fb5-807d-be08533da92a",front:"ā",back:"from, of, since, by",description:"Preposition + abl",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"89e49252-df19-4d60-afa9-3465184fd6b3",front:"ad",back:"to, toward, by, at, till",description:"Preposition + acc",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"8254b449-a6a0-4d43-aade-de78ed8e4e5a",front:"ante",back:"in front of, before",description:"Preposition + acc",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"b7288353-bb93-47cf-b3b2-3d28958deaf1",front:"apud",back:"beside, near, by",description:"Preposition + acc",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"ab3156e9-45e4-4a61-a751-1321b366ef20",front:"circum",back:"around",description:"Preposition + acc",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"45f1e00a-1e66-4dac-a32d-0d064afc4ca8",front:"inter",back:"between, among, during",description:"Preposition + acc",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"51362e82-bad2-481d-bf2d-61b83bc69082",front:"per",back:"trough, by, during",description:"Preposition + acc",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"cce9874a-0a91-4503-af71-d54a4a39d82d",front:"post",back:"behind, after, later",description:"Preposition + acc",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"859091ac-4695-405b-b305-caba3a8dda8f",front:"procul ab",back:"far from",description:"Preposition + abl",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"16dbbaf1-c47a-4dfd-b49d-06b390ce5dca",front:"prope",back:"near, nearby",description:"Preposition + acc",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"77eb2525-4ce0-4025-8409-04f13caab30d",front:"quam?",back:"how?",description:"Interrogative",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"f39930fc-7bdd-440f-b8a8-fefb940a745e",front:"quō?",back:"where (to)?",description:"Interrogative",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"abe117a7-212f-45ab-8909-d3de453d60e1",front:"unde?",back:"from where? whence?",description:"Interrogative",meta:{chapter:"VI"}},{id:"a07d4391-7530-448d-9431-924f2a99a13b",front:"lacrima, -ae",back:"tear",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"de6c030e-c33e-46b8-b071-712b9f04c720",front:"mālum, -ī",back:"apple",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"9624023d-fb7c-4201-9266-684b6ce73990",front:"oculus, -ī",back:"eye",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"84d52785-9908-4879-b4a6-75df4212f270",front:"ōsculum, -ī",back:"kiss",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"f2387982-7818-48c6-833e-e700ad0867fc",front:"ōstiārius, -ī",back:"doorkeeper",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"5789b64a-e914-46e8-9470-c24f6a1a46a1",front:"pirum, -ī",back:"pear",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"91c0884d-adfb-40a6-b088-aaf733289798",front:"speculum, -ī",back:"mirror",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"2de549e3-3043-42c4-a208-bb582cf445a1",front:"dat, dant",back:"give",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"4b36dc72-68eb-407f-85a3-0b2bb1e8b11b",front:"expectat, exspectant",back:"wait (for), expect",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"0f3eb6d4-4cdc-447a-b8f6-b3eb7045490e",front:"lacrimat",back:"cry",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"2f946cca-63a0-4d0d-82b6-95980719a271",front:"tenet, tenent",back:"hold, keep (back)",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"02ef46f9-b796-4b42-a8ad-f1f98e875cf0",front:"terget, tergent",back:"wipe",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"68b06eec-d2fd-4783-99f5-19ae58865e27",front:"claudit, claudunt",back:"shut, close",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"c03aecf3-7fd9-435b-84f8-0a362a74d1ff",front:"currit, currunt",back:"run",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"8ef300c7-2cbd-42d0-9cba-84fbc9daef62",front:"vertit, vertunt",back:"turn",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"6ca0b0fe-5d09-46e0-8e75-e514d9a98083",front:"advenit, adveniunt",back:"arrive",description:"Verb, 4. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"96f122a9-029e-43d0-bb4f-b6d6677daad7",front:"aperit, aperiunt",back:"open, disclose",description:"Verb, 4. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"888106b9-26e4-4aeb-8a96-8c9f82dba12a",front:"adit, adeunt",back:"go to, approach",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"7860e718-0b12-4889-905c-bf8939f4aa99",front:"exit, exeunt",back:"go out",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"3e20960f-4921-4209-8c06-6243cf6c69cb",front:"inest, insunt",back:"be in",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"8e6de0d2-d046-4b21-a7e0-2b62335bea95",front:"fōrmōsus, -a, -um",back:"beautiful",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"1a3e8510-de7a-4907-8521-c9771609994b",front:"plēnus, -a, -um",back:"full (of)",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"d5119de2-fb2e-4209-b50b-e8ad8339fc62",front:"hic, haec, hoc",back:"this",description:"Pronoun (nom)",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"6d22d22f-1744-49ca-81db-8ddc11237568",front:"sē, sibi",back:"himself, herself",description:"Pronoun (acc/abl)",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"af57048e-f2de-4c0e-89e9-985cae7f6a35",front:"immō",back:"no, on the contrary",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"71ee1dcd-ad63-4fdf-b3eb-692f5deac845",front:"illīc",back:"there",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"5c6095b0-dcac-422d-8047-642fa52e3a96",front:"nōn sōlum...sed etiam",back:"not only...but also",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"267ebce1-6ced-44ed-819c-fe319b842071",front:"et...et",back:"both...and",description:"Conjunction",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"46c60ead-aeae-4108-ac07-39cb4e1efdc7",front:"neque...neque",back:"neither...nor",description:"Conjunction",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"d77d8f75-d235-405f-b113-b50cc3cf4d1f",front:"ē",back:"out of, of, since",description:"Preposition + abl",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"7a79bba9-8bb7-44cb-be01-267639822b90",front:"nōnne?",back:"not?",description:"Interrogative",meta:{chapter:"VII"}},{id:"1f3be13d-96dd-4564-a8bf-6825713370d7",front:"gemma, -ae",back:"precious stone, jewel",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"92e805d6-2f27-4552-b335-2a4dacb11510",front:"līnea, -ae",back:"string, line",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"d963c43f-3f98-40fe-b094-1791526516c9",front:"margarīta, -ae",back:"pearl",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"05b72d0d-fff2-4979-991a-1ef3b0ab2875",front:"taberna, -ae",back:"shop, stall",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"669aee67-fea3-43ba-8c5f-a8ec7c08c6e0",front:"ānulus, -ī",back:"ring",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"14849f68-c922-43c2-a062-c0c338fc67a9",front:"collum, -ī",back:"neck",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"0f963055-cc8c-4934-a650-a702d96cea60",front:"digitus, -ī",back:"finger",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"a6803bf5-0222-4ba8-a5ce-04184c24cdbb",front:"ōrnāmentum, -ī",back:"ornament, piece of jewelry",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"6bc1fc7b-10a0-45a4-8cad-17e0e8a340a2",front:"pretium, -ī",back:"price, value",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"3421c6df-b2d2-4864-9d45-5399a1011724",front:"sēstertius, -ī",back:"sesterce (coin)",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"325300e2-cd8b-4d1b-af4e-be099e90c923",front:"tabernārius, -ī",back:"shopkeeper",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"9f808b20-3686-46eb-83fa-42b02f2ed4b3",front:"prōnōmen, prōnōmis",back:"pronoun",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"0e51926b-8c39-44f3-a3b9-1563b6f7f1cb",front:"clāmat, clāmant",back:"shout",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"186b2fb8-e8b6-4637-b46d-040e113d3871",front:"cōnstat, cōnstant",back:"cost, stand firm",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"cffb9ff6-18a6-4b82-92ca-05c4789189fc",front:"mōnstrat, mōnstrant",back:"point out, show",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"b156c869-3039-4641-bdaf-f6f474b9f45e",front:"ornat, ornant",back:"equip, adorn",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"d677aa88-6c2b-46f6-ad9c-3bf2019b50d4",front:"cōnsistit, cōnsistunt",back:"stop, halt",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"39cfd0a8-d98c-408a-ab7f-b6c2e2082537",front:"emit, emunt",back:"buy",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"e61639d8-f4b7-429b-b33c-f4b1ed4dd1b7",front:"ostendit, ostendunt",back:"show",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"88d2810e-fd17-4f35-b082-bce0b96a13b0",front:"vēndit, vēndunt",back:"sell",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"de936a0c-5e3b-4a91-864f-582bd69f6406",front:"aspicit, aspiciunt",back:"look at, look",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"8118f9ca-6e5d-4707-848c-d0a6416b3ca7",front:"accipit, accipiunt",back:"receive",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"ea7515a9-55b2-4101-9f84-3a5589b8b0af",front:"convenit, conveniunt",back:"come together, meet, suit",description:"Verb, 4. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"027c5cab-e0a7-41f8-aaa4-2ff3950e5f97",front:"abit, abeunt",back:"go away",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"02507a54-34a1-4b45-9cee-f07c266a037d",front:"alius, alia, aliud",back:"another, other",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"2ced8425-6aac-4b9d-9e1d-93f4f065e297",front:"gemmātus, -a, -um",back:"set with a jewel",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"28e8513a-34ab-4e80-84cd-ee7536019792",front:"medius, -a, -um",back:"mid, middle",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"ecf858f7-adcd-45b5-ab99-de6d722a3536",front:"pecūniōsus, -a, -um",back:"wealthy",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"41eac466-e332-44cf-8437-6ab7136650e0",front:"quantus, -a, -um",back:"how large, (as large) as",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"5de7e227-79f4-44d3-a43f-d5f124e52795",front:"quārtus, -a, -um",back:"fourth",description:"Adjective, . declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"81d81320-ffcc-4f59-8178-d36fbf288693",front:"tantus, -a, -um",back:"so big, so great",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"a1e8f10c-b664-4e09-a62a-d4859707c2fe",front:"nōnāgintā",back:"ninety",description:"Numeral",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"848d403f-ef96-43b2-84ee-ede11b7bb4c0",front:"octōgintā",back:"eighty",description:"Numeral",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"f97ecece-1a14-4f63-b87c-e08a7a020902",front:"vīgintī",back:"twenty",description:"Numeral",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"766897ef-4dd3-4a43-9b8d-0b5ee420ab0e",front:"ille, illa, illud",back:"that, the one, he",description:"Pronoun (nom)",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"953137b4-ad22-430f-b613-d3aef7341917",front:"nimis",back:"too, too much",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"b24a957a-e491-432b-9b27-a83cb4dd5035",front:"satis",back:"enough",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"c46ee3ae-dfe0-40a2-a5b6-93bbf8b7a62b",front:"aut",back:"or",description:"Conjunction",meta:{chapter:"VIII"}},{id:"779d6494-ed8a-4e5c-9053-044996085cf8",front:"herba, -ae",back:"grass, herb",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"d13dd039-26a2-416c-bd2b-3cc4073408b3",front:"silva, -ae",back:"wood, forest",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"c71188f9-e99d-4f14-8865-b9c9bd3f9ad1",front:"terra, -ae",back:"earth, ground, country",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"0d0f716e-e4c9-4c8d-8c54-1fca840b80c5",front:"umbra, -ae",back:"shade, shadow",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"c940c833-4d03-4394-a08e-6075284237a4",front:"caelum, -ī",back:"sky, heaven",description:"Noun, n/m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"3f23df78-cd6c-4020-a5fa-639acef7c805",front:"campus, -ī",back:"plain",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"2d602e66-821b-4909-bebd-702cf6fd86b0",front:"cibus, -ī",back:"food",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"8493ddd9-1411-4de1-9343-656dc375a0ae",front:"lupus, -ī",back:"wolf",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"dd60a5ac-c560-4d83-bf1a-3940ef0bc4fd",front:"modus, -ī",back:"manner, way",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"669b2d54-a1ef-4da7-88be-44ac608e83f7",front:"rīvus, -ī",back:"river",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"c2529a6b-d72e-49b9-b14b-4887f568006e",front:"vestīgium, -ī",back:"footprint, trace",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"2464a764-0183-4e8c-b8fa-e620472a561b",front:"arbor, arboris",back:"tree",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"620016a8-1593-460f-93b6-9a335b762ec9",front:"canis, canis",back:"dog",description:"Noun, m/f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"a7de4c2f-7c1b-474f-a227-42508b867582",front:"clāmor, clāmoris",back:"shout",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"0670b64c-581e-4773-b590-39a22419a9f0",front:"collis, collis",back:"hill",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"7387c399-eed2-4fe4-8d91-46b0549c309f",front:"dēclīnātiō, dēclīnātiōnis",back:"declension",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"a3ace72c-f70b-4320-9853-fa546c0856cb",front:"dēns, dentis",back:"tooth",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"97aeedf9-024f-4ff6-b605-f7d6ea6335c3",front:"mōns, montis",back:"mountain",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"a9013464-a751-4b53-9447-1fde239429c4",front:"nūbēs, nūbis",back:"cloud",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"67d10bab-1cc1-4a20-a1fa-20881646c153",front:"ovis, ovis",back:"sheep",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"b130dd55-e3c3-4eaf-b723-9c7dc93b959a",front:"pānis, pānis",back:"bread, loaf",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"3bd827b1-1683-4d36-87b7-ea750ae8b4e5",front:"pāstor, pāstōris",back:"shepherd",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"7f7436cc-6870-47b8-9c53-dc62eb568081",front:"sōl, sōlis",back:"sun",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"1b2cd2c8-0497-4737-a729-ad21f9eadd2f",front:"timor, timōris",back:"fear",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"a8f94a55-6a9c-40ba-a0bd-2a5917f57a5b",front:"vallis, vallis",back:"valley",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"df60e57b-e06d-400f-9963-7c492987b0a4",front:"bālat, -ant",back:"bleat",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"3108677c-cafb-400b-826a-6ce614b70f77",front:"dēclīnat, -ant",back:"decline, inflect",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"373ee66f-479b-4c9e-9657-e4f970608d8c",front:"errat, -ant",back:"wander, stray",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"4f902cc2-5c73-412d-8d4b-e9caf0674b40",front:"lātrat, -ant",back:"bark",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"fae107d6-3ad4-4f37-9a9a-ab1c716db549",front:"ululat, -ant",back:"howl",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"0002629a-4486-4dba-b185-88e95f30e0f1",front:"iacet, -ent",back:"lie",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"c9f9cb41-b2e8-4d5f-a559-0e691e115247",front:"lūcet, -ent",back:"shine",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"8fca02d8-c6b8-4993-8312-9ee7806b165c",front:"accurit, -unt",back:"come running",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"95389ad7-99e1-4085-8023-d0249cb6bec7",front:"bibit, -unt",back:"drink",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"edec43a7-4c5d-4da4-bd9d-e0d821bec3bd",front:"dūcit, -unt",back:"guide, lead, draw, trace",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"812219ae-80f7-4a55-bdb9-4eb41d730d8a",front:"impōnit, -unt",back:"place (in/on), put",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"1905c151-b24d-4306-a311-d1baf228e0af",front:"petit, -unt",back:"make for, aim at, attack, seek, ask for, request",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"1408cac9-b587-476c-b8f6-1000c93a50d2",front:"quaerit, -unt",back:"look for, seek, ask (for)",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"9b2da1d5-95e7-4406-821e-02b775604182",front:"relinquit, -unt",back:"leave",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"781bab92-0594-4f77-a1d7-0082906ccf78",front:"reperit, -iunt",back:"find",description:"Verb, 4. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"5211065e-a467-413c-bc10-252630356674",front:"ēst, edunt",back:"eat",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"c4f7c0d4-a8e5-4335-93d1-c68cc322f67d",front:"niger, -gra, -grum",back:"black",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"28e28808-a4d3-4e41-96c8-733551348054",front:"albus, -a, -um",back:"white",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"bd54efd7-8534-4bd6-8b7b-c37540f254ec",front:"ūndēcentum",back:"ninety-nine",description:"Numeral",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"3f81a696-3c2e-458c-83bd-c43980db4d69",front:"ipse, ipsa, ipsum",back:"myself, yourself, etc; the very, the actual",description:"Pronoun (nom)",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"bcd14586-01a0-4246-a7fa-60812fd3985e",front:"procul",back:"far (from), far away",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"29e05c27-c930-43f0-8426-3a8a4562b910",front:"sub",back:"under, at the foot of, near",description:"Preposition + acc/abl",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"0688cba9-e53a-4108-acf5-09887b3199a5",front:"suprā",back:"above",description:"Preposition + acc",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"4a4869b0-3c61-4c28-8f35-3d5b0f7c7a9a",front:"dum",back:"while, as long as",description:"Conjunction",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"0e905232-ffaa-4221-9447-8477d7c8c770",front:"ut",back:"like, as",description:"Conjunction",meta:{chapter:"IX"}},{id:"80cf9e17-1540-4bf6-a168-e2f6a47a3e6c",front:"āla, -ae",back:"wing",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"6f93a174-57fb-4f18-806c-0e323146af49",front:"anima, -ae",back:"breath, life, soul",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"5b3fbb87-511a-41d8-85f5-dc59e571c13d",front:"aquila, -ae",back:"eagle",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"a97be786-73dc-4441-8991-5b82a921f8d0",front:"bēstia, -ae",back:"beast, animal",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"10bc06ff-2301-4758-b286-53c96133c8b8",front:"cauda, -ae",back:"tail",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"01fcd637-5307-4e63-9401-8b391bdcfedf",front:"fera, -ae",back:"wild animal",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"04b09e8a-a837-4ea8-b616-4c1c17605b56",front:"pila, -ae",back:"ball",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"2fad2673-3d2a-4be2-ae08-09db490e514f",front:"asinus, -ī",back:"ass, donkey",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"283cf4bc-4b31-46fe-aa5f-f5acc1dfb1fe",front:"deus, -ī",back:"god",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"2e0d12d9-3c81-4b9c-a7ed-51f70b6b12a9",front:"folium, -ī",back:"leaf",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"6efb91ab-0c96-495d-9c53-978d3b7c99ce",front:"lectus, -ī",back:"bed, couch",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"d7fb106a-71d2-452a-a284-e84471ed0da2",front:"nīdus, -ī",back:"nest",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"6541ece9-0994-4cb6-9d9f-fd8567df248e",front:"nūntius, -ī",back:"message, messenger",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"cb719479-1779-4700-98b4-4e1eb52dd5be",front:"ōvum, -ī",back:"egg",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"53908c4e-a814-46ee-9352-65e748d1063d",front:"petasus, -ī",back:"hat with a brim",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"411ca52a-4057-4dd4-a3d8-3dd2e0d8e6ec",front:"pullus, -ī",back:"young (of an animal)",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"32c41a06-389f-4789-8c36-ff60f2052849",front:"rāmus, -ī",back:"branch, bough",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"3192292a-7400-4f43-ba30-7baa1bb7aafd",front:"āēr, āeris",back:"air",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"0715186a-14bc-46a5-9e97-050c32033c83",front:"animal, animālis",back:"animal, living being",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"63c67105-e1e6-4aab-9adc-ab9a96e4121e",front:"avis, avis",back:"bird",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"f883dab3-9985-4057-837f-3214739af5af",front:"flūmen, flūminis",back:"river",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"f83d1e2c-6329-4b65-816f-8fd3503dedcb",front:"homō, hominis",back:"human being, person",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"330700bc-2c37-4d54-93d4-7cdba6516f8c",front:"leō, leōnis",back:"lion",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"30ca2dfb-3153-49b8-b85f-fbb106656d09",front:"mare, maris",back:"sea",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"380b4eb1-e46d-4bab-9824-1b35da99691f",front:"mercātor, mercātōris",back:"merchant",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"8187abda-dee0-416e-83f4-39b9697a124b",front:"pēs, pedis",back:"foot",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"4df46fab-1041-4060-86fe-8992e17601c8",front:"piscis, piscis",back:"fish",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"6fe21392-74c0-471b-a9fd-1a5ac8d83288",front:"pulmō, pulmπōnis",back:"lung",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"f1eaecdd-8a95-45c1-b6d2-a17462670ee7",front:"vōx, vōcis",back:"voice",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"09bf8bf8-02fd-44e0-ac54-230af87e6798",front:"natat, natāre",back:"swim",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"32c61e71-cd2b-43cb-8361-78afabc9b259",front:"occultat, occultāre",back:"hide",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"c2bbda2e-3f43-440a-af33-476dc4224625",front:"spīrat, spīrāre",back:"breathe",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"07050a88-e3f0-4404-a756-cf6e8e637454",front:"volat, volare",back:"fly",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"9ed0a788-a6f7-4563-b689-f5db00df0f16",front:"audet, audēre",back:"dare, venture",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"da6ad6d2-2630-4017-b13c-2c60626e8078",front:"movet, movēre",back:"move, stir",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"c2fc0077-fa08-4d32-864b-5e23dcb97520",front:"sustinet, sustinēre",back:"support, sustain, endure",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"e816f66c-f848-4a12-bc55-31030187b5ae",front:"ascendit, ascendere",back:"climb, go up, mount",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"351d58bc-0440-43b9-acf3-af20d5cc1ee3",front:"cadit, cadere",back:"fall",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"7f9188ad-5804-4146-9d82-439bb1a8e838",front:"canit, canere",back:"sing (of), crow, play",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"592b4b77-c4ca-4e37-a0a4-59cfb4429391",front:"lūdit, lūdere",back:"play",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"8a262309-ad5e-4c14-8f8e-2546f45de958",front:"vīvit, vīvere",back:"live, be alive",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"12b0d651-357d-4c4b-a811-3192b3f16188",front:"capit, capere",back:"take, catch, capture",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"ccd327fa-8f31-44c2-a4ef-e9e655e27bb6",front:"facit, facere",back:"make, do, cause",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"f4828d3f-5b1f-4bbf-9811-e9b81b5fc2ea",front:"parit, parere",back:"give birth to, lay",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"fedb15c7-9fbd-4aeb-881a-91b6ed466206",front:"necesse est",back:"it is necessary",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"0e5f2212-1f66-48c3-a9dc-24e8f2563f38",front:"potest, possunt, posse",back:"be able",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"88207d1e-1a8a-4af2-aca0-f25ad7ad90cd",front:"vult, volunt",back:"want, be willing",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"483c8b8a-4e3e-4599-b975-538839065f53",front:"crassus, -a, -um",back:"thick, fat",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"c6b6b46f-b23e-4c7e-abae-a5d97724adea",front:"ferus, -a, -um",back:"wild",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"3cdbbffe-69a3-49e6-96ad-e6fc5b0cc91c",front:"mortuus, -a, -um",back:"dead",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"12df87f9-1431-4428-9ee3-ddaaff6ca2b4",front:"perterritus, -a, -um",back:"terrified",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"1bb16e86-2012-47c6-8803-c03d3ee78e77",front:"vīvus, -a, -um",back:"living, alive",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"efb95b78-5f75-4350-aea0-42fc5551b7c3",front:"tenuis, -e",back:"thin",description:"Adjective, 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"4f0771e9-400c-4b6c-b2bc-34cb747bff8d",front:"nēmo",back:"no one",description:"Pronoun",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"a4d0e0ca-19d2-424d-b5ae-1605280808e9",front:"ergō",back:"therefore, so",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"93379982-6371-4db0-af40-762392af4b3a",front:"cum",back:"when",description:"Conjunction",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"32e7ddd2-305b-4857-b5a5-f78f43f50712",front:"enim",back:"for",description:"Conjunction",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"f3dfa1be-93fa-40e3-896b-659e9df6f1c7",front:"quod",back:"because",description:"Conjunction",meta:{chapter:"X"}},{id:"abdb851a-af23-4098-81af-0cb4a20b3872",front:"gena, -ae",back:"cheek",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"a9d40701-fd02-465d-9de3-df059dbc9a8e",front:"lingua, -ae",back:"tongue, language",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"91198781-610a-43ad-8bda-8c1573d3c219",front:"vēna, -ae",back:"vein",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"4be3c7a8-8650-49b8-b049-de07363821f7",front:"bracchium, -ī",back:"arm",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"a313d589-4cf3-494f-815e-11ab14204bac",front:"capillus, -ī",back:"hair",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"26b336f8-6bcc-4271-8053-4fe2242e8bab",front:"cerebrum, -ī",back:"brain",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"e66a2c89-a241-4ca0-bc0c-f4b6511dafce",front:"culter, cultrī",back:"knife",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"017f69ae-4087-4bd4-891a-cbde0ed52c77",front:"labrum, -ī",back:"lip",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"fce582d4-cf7a-480f-a6f8-031e3f0630b1",front:"medicus, -ī",back:"doctor",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"8f0102ba-cd32-446f-a4d6-533f77f3c6eb",front:"membrum, -ī",back:"limb",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"72c57e1e-cdf0-49c8-b49a-f63df4626d61",front:"pōculum, -ī",back:"cup",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"d98303b1-04d9-4d8f-84f6-025737437b77",front:"auris, auris",back:"ear",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"8f39288e-6e1a-4b0c-aeb6-6e394570eaa3",front:"caput, capitis",back:"head",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"a9cca15b-be91-42fc-bf0a-7ba488b0f844",front:"color, colōris",back:"color",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"e637632a-8077-4082-b630-8091556c7433",front:"cor, cordis",back:"heart",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"08efcd03-89de-4c65-80d5-7b6408ad4dd4",front:"corpus, corporis",back:"body",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"94a2b0db-7732-470d-af42-77082a549541",front:"crūs, crūris",back:"leg",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"48c97f97-8160-4437-96ff-f80307522ecd",front:"frōns, frontis",back:"forehead",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"36bc64e6-b2cd-4842-bcf7-0b47b973d43f",front:"iecur, iecoris",back:"liver",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"7c814731-78ee-4e01-9d82-2f532e1c93d6",front:"ōs, ōris",back:"mouth",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"f6cdc123-4558-4c47-bc54-c0d531bf9c97",front:"pectus, pectoris",back:"chest",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"48dbff86-b3f6-4188-886d-abc8d857d124",front:"sanguis, sanguinis",back:"blood",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"2ed7bf48-04cf-42ba-9cb1-b6524c250358",front:"venter, ventris",back:"stomach",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"382d4875-4ce8-44ec-8a0b-b653320144e0",front:"viscera, viscerum",back:"internal organs",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"5c1b396b-fb8a-4a51-83d6-f3f0504c770f",front:"manus",back:"hand",description:"Noun, f., 4. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"57826354-00cb-44f5-a268-f6001e2d8ddf",front:"aegrōtat, aegrōtāre",back:"be ill",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"0fa83f03-2b40-4c52-8b25-38b8d16aed65",front:"palpitat, palpitāre",back:"beat, throb",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"c369cf20-9b6f-45cb-abe0-0ac7c3f46740",front:"putat, putāre",back:"think, suppose",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"7868e486-f25c-493e-bd79-fa1eac6be1dc",front:"sānat, sānāre",back:"heal, cure",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"50f70377-823a-421b-92b2-92789e950a7e",front:"spectat, spectāre",back:"watch, look at",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"aff36475-c471-4285-840b-1b79b383d64e",front:"stat, stāre",back:"stand",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"4662997d-365c-4379-9465-d95fd4d32ca9",front:"dēterget, dētergēre",back:"wipe off",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"f7c33a5b-8765-474b-99df-83ef7d88f19d",front:"dolet, dolēre",back:"hurt, feel pain, grieve",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"67656579-d404-49ee-95f4-57107cb481ca",front:"gaudet, gaudēre",back:"be glad, be pleased",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"2d39c5fd-fc0c-4473-a41c-35f96169b83a",front:"horret, horrēre",back:"bristle, shudder (at)",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"09ee8e0e-08da-484c-bc3e-5c4c65e286df",front:"iubet, iubēre",back:"order, tell",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"89b326e2-4e0f-40a7-93fa-183b6eb3367f",front:"sedet, sedēre",back:"sit",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"7b7ab594-fcf5-4210-9fbc-5f1a73989e97",front:"appōnit, appōnere",back:"place (on), serve",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"25d48e53-3acb-4b10-a111-303ea53ce33d",front:"arcessit, arcessere",back:"send for, fetch",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"7691c928-452a-46a7-b936-d9f38c6095b9",front:"dīcit, dīcere",back:"say, call, speak",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"2d8015d8-f74c-41f1-89b7-297b25704b3d",front:"fluit, fluere",back:"flow",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"af190356-fa6f-4e61-aad6-9d6c05184a6c",front:"tangit, tangere",back:"touch",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"4f65fb88-b882-4381-8f73-b71dc018f020",front:"revenit, revenīre",back:"come back",description:"Verb, 4. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"00e2658e-84c4-4852-98c8-ced2e621052d",front:"sentit, sentīre",back:"feel, sense, think",description:"Verb, 4. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"b12a2d8f-4a89-42b4-9f23-1e6c71c04fb2",front:"potest, posse",back:"be able",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"b89ebffb-2e8a-4277-afb9-22f54131aea0",front:"aeger, -gra, -grum",back:"sick, ill",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"b65a0ab7-f7c2-4f81-9afa-26509fd63b05",front:"hūmānus, -a, -um",back:"human",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"2d3bb951-2ea4-45ad-8e0d-4ef9645b177e",front:"noster, nostra, nostrum",back:"our, ours",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"d32eca1b-a844-437f-85ff-12228ed0102d",front:"ruber, rubra, rubrum",back:"red",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"152a20c3-601a-453d-96de-267a1d6b6897",front:"sānus, -a, -um",back:"healthy, well",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"7f93e170-88eb-4d46-979f-be7055850957",front:"stultus, -a, -um",back:"stupid, foolish",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"cc71ef76-1683-4687-b932-468a314a6c11",front:"bene",back:"well",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"524dd6d1-cde6-4963-986e-5f3bb6c21ae5",front:"male",back:"badly, ill",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"b3bc512a-6bf8-4e90-bfb0-96e9da151392",front:"modo",back:"only, just",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"b6ed630b-f508-42ab-b933-70ba1ed4c736",front:"dē",back:"(down) from, of, about",description:"Preposition + abl",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"1ec73c3a-7e42-4e61-9143-5e7c4e0c73b2",front:"īnfrā",back:"below",description:"Preposition + acc",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"27add6e7-c607-4fa7-871f-6abe5de4fd53",front:"super",back:"on (top of), above",description:"Preposition + acc",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"75893631-46b7-404c-ac1c-b2d74c66e79a",front:"atque, ac",back:"and, as, than",description:"Conjunction",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"3357f355-e6ba-4974-8616-4f6f340b2396",front:"nec",back:"and/but not, nor, not",description:"Conjunction",meta:{chapter:"XI"}},{id:"5c387609-785c-4435-9962-05674c5b2f4b",front:"fossa, -ae",back:"ditch, trench",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"941558d5-b040-4f25-a022-d93dbaf57b15",front:"hasta, -ae",back:"lance",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"8e7c32c1-e28d-4cbb-8c03-31caed8a78f3",front:"patria, -ae",back:"native country/town",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"315e9f44-f041-4c36-b0db-588fcb892a64",front:"sagitta, -ae",back:"arrow",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"583bba65-b8f1-45ee-8271-9f5168d62ecf",front:"avunculus, -ī",back:"(maternal) uncle",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"2370d1e4-32db-4de7-89dc-f06fcf1dbe53",front:"arma, -ōrum",back:"arms",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"4d08ba91-c5e4-42fb-9d42-79f472680542",front:"bellum, -ī",back:"war",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"3d04c33a-956e-4c9f-916a-76f87ef75c67",front:"castra, -ōrum",back:"camp",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"cdb0b08f-381b-434c-8969-d48110985eb2",front:"gladius, -ī",back:"sword",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"a3574596-35d7-4a0a-a90a-77564503a521",front:"pīlum, -ī",back:"spear, javelin",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"19820635-418b-4945-917c-5987474ef003",front:"pugnus, -ī",back:"fist",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"1e24d029-cbeb-43e3-86c4-b61c81feb46b",front:"scūtum, -ī",back:"shield",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"8439df7b-d186-49e9-8fae-3c1bb9f65f5d",front:"vāllum, -ī",back:"rampart",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"d17fb6c8-9325-4a1d-a83c-cbf3f3d0e736",front:"cognōmen, -inis",back:"surname",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"d3566cca-4148-4241-b855-8a540a76dfa7",front:"dux, ducis",back:"leader, chief, general",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"18513792-bbc1-4e32-abb6-43dceff38f57",front:"eques, equitis",back:"horseman",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"c5fa6243-4b6f-4fa3-8c3c-a0130498708f",front:"frāter, frātris",back:"brother",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"8bb3c0b0-d01c-41f3-9ca3-2d2a15e813a1",front:"fīnis, fīnis",back:"boundary, limit, end",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"7c3491f4-614a-4959-948a-b6060f5b3e24",front:"hostis, hostis",back:"enemy",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"a97690a6-9a4d-401e-aef1-1734cfe07d2f",front:"lātus, lāteris",back:"side, flank",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"2564129a-32f7-45b0-a530-872e4d1c7acb",front:"mīles, mīlitis",back:"soldier",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"9eeb5b09-2b40-47f8-b520-5977d09ca3ac",front:"mīlia, mīlium",back:"thousand",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"a29af032-6529-44c6-a982-5bffae5dc9f1",front:"nōmen, nōminis",back:"name",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"ea0c83de-a23b-41e7-9c7e-36163fe637ce",front:"pars, partis",back:"part, direction",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"05515e7e-82ea-45cc-8a61-fc67f67c173a",front:"pedes, peditis",back:"footsoldier",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"f13e2b65-36a8-4463-9a01-6ab8feae569b",front:"praenōmen, praenōminis",back:"first name",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"12f18417-05ea-484a-a0fe-de1d63ff459c",front:"soror, sorōris",back:"sister",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"5617bc35-3db3-42bd-96f7-0cce5236a0b9",front:"arcus, arcūs",back:"bow",description:"Noun, m., 4. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"044d3a1a-6b9a-4537-adc6-1ceb23bc3363",front:"equitātus, equitātūs",back:"cavalry",description:"Noun, m., 4. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"34d8ce9e-608d-43bd-a61b-7b9e35862002",front:"exercitus, exercitūs",back:"army",description:"Noun, m., 4. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"dfa8185d-0b5d-4272-9610-ada1c7385b13",front:"impetus, impetūs",back:"attack, charge",description:"Noun, m., 4. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"3cc429b3-5c28-4f94-9dce-79309d53374f",front:"metus, metūs",back:"fear",description:"Noun, m., 4. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"04f3370c-b526-48f4-a11a-a78e59632620",front:"passus, passūs",back:"pace",description:"Noun, m., 4. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"13580caa-553c-486a-aea8-e841a64baa21",front:"versus, versūs",back:"line, verse",description:"Noun, m., 4. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"c79258d4-760d-4f7d-8504-349f04d79c37",front:"pugnat, pugnāre",back:"fight",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"2eb3a417-25ef-44ad-9df1-9ce6558a8793",front:"mīlitat, mīlitāre",back:"serve as a soldier",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"a59246c9-fce0-44d7-8fa4-ae259e5c84cb",front:"expugnat, expugnāre",back:"conquer",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"eff585f9-7e87-4be9-86b3-7f51f13be2ea",front:"oppugnat, oppugnāre",back:"attack",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"9df0b14a-820a-4066-956c-d029e90e3f5b",front:"incolit, incolere",back:"inhabit",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"d6a2fe2e-2f74-4a99-88b1-ed5819c51499",front:"dīvidit, dīvidere",back:"divide",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"d09726f9-f305-4755-b543-b7d64f065b4b",front:"metuit, metuere",back:"fear",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"a1866ea1-c858-4238-b949-77a0d8b4b49b",front:"dēfendit, dēfendere",back:"defend",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"f33374c5-3765-4dc1-a5e3-ff2888eb63a9",front:"iacit, iacere",back:"throw, hurl",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"b36107f2-0b74-4717-bebe-d868e389c3f3",front:"fugit, fugere",back:"run away, flee",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"6b8f5b96-a393-4827-a415-1d34cfff656f",front:"fert, ferre",back:"carry, bring, bear",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"ea4f43b0-9441-454e-97ae-db9a351c865f",front:"altus, -a, -um",back:"high, tall, deep",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"3353cfd8-3d94-4348-8a26-9128d34efd82",front:"armātus, -a, -um",back:"armed",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"89271588-4f4e-4cef-b0ab-e6ad03c4a0e6",front:"barbarus, -a, -um",back:"foreign, barbarian",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"e064bb2c-6958-4bf9-818b-7e4863bbb594",front:"lātus, -a, -um",back:"wide",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"a7bb9d17-4851-4997-aaea-9cd07674160d",front:"vester, -tra, -trum",back:"your, yours",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"75b7d0a2-8b12-410d-9ddb-6b6158a3f563",front:"brevis, -e",back:"short",description:"Adjective, 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"ecf9e373-602b-4715-bd0c-b5b884333db7",front:"fortis, -e",back:"strong, brave",description:"Adjective, 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"8fda03ed-d397-46ef-8afc-f81f2e457217",front:"gravis, -e",back:"heavy, severe, grave",description:"Adjective, 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"55c922b2-fd6c-416f-9f8a-7685a639c419",front:"levis, -e",back:"light, slight",description:"Adjective, 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"ec77dcff-6286-4b92-b06d-1ca5bd92e4cd",front:"trīstis, -e",back:"sad",description:"Adjective, 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"947884ee-379f-43fe-9351-68dff2970e3a",front:"contrā",back:"against",description:"Preposition + acc",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"0ac45ecd-f605-445d-97b9-3868be2f1ad0",front:"ac",back:"and, as, than",description:"Conjunction",meta:{chapter:"XII"}},{id:"f49baeab-4cbb-47ad-b892-e1e8fcda88e1",front:"fōrma, -ae",back:"form, shape, figure",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"490b0771-f854-4651-aa7e-918fc3b7365a",front:"hōra, -ae",back:"hour",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"77917f28-30c9-4d6d-ab6f-bcfbc419df11",front:"kalendae, -ārum",back:"the 1st of the month",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"268eeb90-8aa1-4814-b8a8-fd77d10b034e",front:"lūna, -ae",back:"moon",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"bd52791c-6bc7-496d-8044-1cd3f33de415",front:"nōnae, -ārum",back:"5th/7th of the month",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"acc05569-618e-4753-9c37-4295671f3fa1",front:"stēlla, -ae",back:"star",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"a85a36b1-3b8a-435c-97f7-530e0f73269d",front:"aequinoctium, -ī",back:"equinox",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"84afd04a-0ce0-4fe9-b5c3-d160fcb5a2c7",front:"annus, -ī",back:"year",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"898d0d40-1322-45e5-a6cc-cace96626af8",front:"autumnus, -ī",back:"autumn",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"97749632-8079-4949-b527-41b14f42322d",front:"initium, -ī",back:"beginning",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"d12e3015-a338-4801-ab1e-8247d8cd3e2d",front:"saeculum, -ī",back:"century",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"c4253341-cafe-4006-ac1d-a783b6e45e28",front:"vesper, vesperī",back:"evening",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"023f1554-b556-40c9-9767-80931f2e3cec",front:"aestās, aestātis",back:"summer",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"2b47fe13-a146-4bab-b571-31b69c1fb8b6",front:"hiems, hiemis",back:"winter",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"03b821c0-5d25-4267-91f3-1ee5c1cd6fc1",front:"imber, imbris",back:"rain, shower",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"c0b9b610-c930-4a51-8408-3f60c56fb23f",front:"lūx, lūcis",back:"light, daylight",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"63e54377-8809-43ae-9fae-3f1432977994",front:"mēnsis, mēnsis",back:"month",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"223e97e1-d9d9-43ea-a6b4-2a182dd067e2",front:"nix, nivis",back:"snow",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"0e1bb7fe-7e51-46cc-88a5-d2ac1dff9cb3",front:"nox, noctis",back:"night",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"cfba7877-517f-4bd7-88ea-6cf8391729a6",front:"tempus, temporis",back:"time",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"dc7e4c1b-ec36-4772-a511-c6c017a97dd9",front:"urbs, urbis",back:"city",description:"Noun, f., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"02ec8a4d-4406-4475-a199-d577b4aaa9e7",front:"vēr, vēris",back:"spring",description:"Noun, n., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"2c5dc00c-4d45-4bc0-aaa9-6b1c25494b0c",front:"īdūs, īduum",back:"13th/15th of the month",description:"Noun, f., 4. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"7fa8eb64-3ba5-41e1-8e7e-8c085449b1ad",front:"lacus, -ūs",back:"lake",description:"Noun, m., 4. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"9d3fba1a-8d64-4c76-b14f-b12be2661320",front:"diēs, -ēī",back:"day, date",description:"Noun, m., 5. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"8fee16fc-6736-424a-bfee-aa9d26a1e729",front:"faciēs, -ēī",back:"face",description:"Noun, f., 5. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"d461f4cb-e58b-4e88-b1bd-94a5252120f6",front:"glaciēs, -ēī",back:"ice",description:"Noun, f., 5. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"9eccefb2-7fd4-4fde-8b34-61438a11670d",front:"merīdiēs, -ēī",back:"midday, noon, south",description:"Noun, m., 5. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"a4527ea3-f60d-4d4a-8504-bded35b3fb3b",front:"īndēclīnābilis",back:"indeclinable",description:"Noun, ., 5. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"49da0855-3e32-40ff-84ab-31861ad6b3c8",front:"māne",back:"morning",description:"Noun, n., 5. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"429b552b-df94-4bc8-9386-b408ef2b2324",front:"illustrāt, illustrāre",back:"illustrate, make clear",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"1685a5a7-5860-4ada-8c07-9e08e8ceed6b",front:"nōminat, nōmināre",back:"name, call",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"9f234349-a870-460e-b271-a3a0d21bd639",front:"incipit, incipere",back:"begin",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"f22d89de-f5e1-4e17-81f1-5b615fdf4145",front:"operit, operīre",back:"cover",description:"Verb, 4. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"8abfb1aa-23c6-4fe4-a1ce-8011a7b16583",front:"erat, erant",back:"was, were",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"534dbbcd-6cbe-4174-bf52-98bd9c8b5b90",front:"vult, velle",back:"want, be willing",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"ade24240-de6f-45cc-ae1e-d5ca3d19e911",front:"aequus, -a, -um",back:"equal, calm",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"5ad2e15e-cc90-4e38-ac11-825e5926fc2a",front:"calidus, -a, -um",back:"warm, hot, f. hot water",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"f11598bc-1cae-4289-a887-4715e23e50f4",front:"clārus, -a, -um",back:"bright, clear, loud",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"862c5263-a437-49b8-9f00-d7d50e25ca3c",front:"decimus, -a, -um",back:"tenth",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"a044cfd4-650c-455d-907d-6b88e51b49cf",front:"dīmidus, -a, -um",back:"half",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"2f2282aa-92f1-4cd4-8681-0b0034e58c0b",front:"duodecimus, -a, -um",back:"twelfth",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"05535f5e-04f4-4e08-aad2-5cd4dc749587",front:"exiguus, -a, -um",back:"small, scanty",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"4e31c407-13ce-400f-8ebc-5876878bdbba",front:"frīgidus, -a, -um",back:"cold, chilly, cool",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"f59fe6a7-956b-46ce-8356-684a8cedb31d",front:"nōnus, -a, -um",back:"ninth",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"653c372a-ae59-4f69-aa3b-fec6018edf98",front:"obscūrus, -a, -um",back:"dark",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"3caf6d27-984a-4cda-beb4-eadb6f1b39af",front:"octāvus, -a, -um",back:"eigth",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"41394729-3411-45d6-8b21-39527f01548f",front:"postrēmus, -a, -um",back:"last",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"8bac31a8-247b-4339-bbf1-4ba72aea49c6",front:"quīntus, -a, -um",back:"fifth",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"a0a5b5c9-6478-493b-b5e9-7427f4fdf0c1",front:"septimus, -a, -um",back:"seventh",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"3a1f5a42-15e9-4d1e-b7c2-71caebc9bbdf",front:"sextus, -a, -um",back:"sixth",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"c2990817-82de-47fb-ad96-7a54dbe9f45e",front:"tōtus, -a, -um",back:"the wole of, all",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"ef7f9284-b7c5-4632-9998-a5db3b6bb09e",front:"ūndecimus, -a, -um",back:"eleventh",description:"Adjective, . declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"01acf8c2-621e-4328-9c58-9aa18b6aa847",front:"īndēclīnābilis, -e",back:"indeclinable",description:"Adjective, 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"a07d61cb-6491-4a26-a5b6-21818e16689e",front:"ducentī, -ae, -a",back:"two hundred",description:"Numeral",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"3d1e8c50-fe85-41f9-bb8b-cfe2da699566",front:"sexāgintā",back:"sixty",description:"Numeral",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"fdc34cd8-e3b1-4d40-a48d-89e0620b3e2b",front:"trecentī, -ae, -a",back:"three hundred",description:"Numeral",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"fc9844f6-0f91-4737-b4cc-8d976c93d2a2",front:"trīgintā",back:"thirty",description:"Numeral",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"dd73b7d1-ed95-4b53-b903-9c91bc90ed20",front:"ūndecim",back:"eleven",description:"Numeral",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"94a90ed3-4fc2-4996-9448-f58389b71a49",front:"item",back:"likewise, also",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"afd76791-b097-4eca-a986-bb633162dc5f",front:"māne",back:"in the morning",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"9b0c0dc2-d03e-4e1d-b365-da062e580f98",front:"nunc",back:"now",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"79631516-6dce-4542-b8b6-18fa878bd435",front:"quandō",back:"when, as",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"769539f7-ccb5-402a-b9fa-44db1e7655d5",front:"tunc",back:"then",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"ac3b04c5-41fa-420f-9cb5-440507a265ee",front:"igitur",back:"therefore, then, so",description:"Conjunction",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"30d5e726-c111-4cba-a7a0-d0d735a0ca1b",front:"vel",back:"or",description:"Conjunction",meta:{chapter:"XIII"}},{id:"c7fa1305-bc3c-4548-9914-0236038d3498",front:"rēgula, -ae",back:"ruler",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"dfb05316-0b7b-47d1-828d-f76143ef16bf",front:"tabula, -ae",back:"writing tablet",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"eb9cb2e1-0e9e-4bda-9cfa-db3949b5f7af",front:"toga, -ae",back:"toga",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"509e2614-3569-4ace-af9f-e7dac5d5bec0",front:"tunica, -ae",back:"tunic",description:"Noun, f., 1. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"1fcfc893-4ded-4bcc-9a67-8d630bd5fb8e",front:"calceus, -ī",back:"shoe",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"ddc3d322-3525-46f9-a527-9e5a180df768",front:"gallus, -ī",back:"cock, rooster",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"fdb24ef4-a1fd-4d85-abd0-958a639afe11",front:"partipicum, -ī",back:"participle",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"00e3b3c1-d01e-47f6-865d-c18df0af1b43",front:"stilus, -ī",back:"stylus",description:"Noun, m., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"3581bafa-2112-4157-9a36-0cb6171854b9",front:"vestīmentum, -ī",back:"garment, clothing",description:"Noun, n., 2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"2787dfa2-b586-48f7-92af-b58e6fbb397d",front:"parentēs, -um",back:"parents",description:"Noun, m., 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"3e9705bf-e4d9-418d-980b-b6d6b2d2f37c",front:"rēs, reī",back:"thing, matter, affair",description:"Noun, f., 5. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"0d1aac20-8152-49e0-ad9a-c30f814df82b",front:"nihil",back:"nothing",description:"Noun, n., indecl. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"8c9f9a2f-4fa8-4ba9-b6d6-a909d5f575f1",front:"cubat, cubāre",back:"lie (in bed)",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"1fb40686-3c65-4500-8cdc-9b2b3878a395",front:"vigilat, vigilāre",back:"be awake",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"db3bada4-69bb-45d6-9992-4c4914f98b64",front:"excitat, excitāre",back:"wake up, arouse",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"ca6ca88d-65c2-4be5-90ff-241e11fb30d0",front:"lavat, lavāre",back:"wash, bathe",description:"Verb, 1. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"0953615c-7502-4787-bec1-ada0e4d819f3",front:"valet, valēre",back:"be strong, be well",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"78443b7b-a0f7-4bee-8142-352cceb66efe",front:"solet, solēre",back:"be accustomed",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"c3dce5af-6598-4aa5-b406-e780d7418695",front:"frīget, frīgēre",back:"be cold",description:"Verb, 2. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"4044640c-d60d-4eac-8d1a-44036d847853",front:"surgit, surgere",back:"rise, get up",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"056c7c67-20b1-41aa-b2cf-30e5087828e9",front:"mergit, mergere",back:"dip, plunge, sink",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"e2133b5b-21f1-40c1-a7f3-bc4be021d473",front:"poscit, poscere",back:"demand, call for",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"bdb7fec3-a399-4f5d-9c44-0e0bfbd41606",front:"induit, induere",back:"put on (clothes)",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"e1ab50d8-d20b-4515-9c18-3f52d564e701",front:"gerit, gerere",back:"carry, wear, carry on, do",description:"Verb, 3. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"75839900-eae8-47c0-a2e6-876151c3f9c3",front:"vestit, vestīre",back:"dress",description:"Verb, 4. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"dc5aa8d3-47ec-4567-b9c7-e862ad0ae185",front:"affert, afferre",back:"bring (to, forward)",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"3039ab8d-a784-444d-9ee3-1c0f4496f175",front:"inquit, inquiunt",back:"(he/she) says/said",description:"Verb, irr. conjugation",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"0f6fed9b-6367-47a7-9672-ec3a4033c9d9",front:"apertus, -a, -um",back:"open",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"241f1406-7f9a-44a5-8b45-b3c72b60ee10",front:"clausus, -a, -um",back:"closed, shut",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"a668316d-6d30-4962-bc40-9179dc9504ef",front:"sordidus, -a, -um",back:"dirty, mean, base",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"0dcc5d17-a563-4d29-a45c-6c7b47cba78c",front:"pūrus, -a, -um",back:"clean, pure",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"ea0de9bb-21f9-4354-b8b0-5677214fe748",front:"nūdus, -a, -um",back:"naked",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"646b5136-9c96-4db5-baf5-6476736aee24",front:"togātus, -a, -um",back:"wearing the toga",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"8ed77b85-5a7e-4e31-9ebb-bb21f9a1fc9f",front:"dexter, -tra, -trum",back:"right, the right hand",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"92245371-a4e1-4ab9-8b9e-731dd767ade7",front:"sinister, -tra, -trum",back:"left, the left hand",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"06dba014-adbb-45ba-a477-4b32f40458ab",front:"neuter, -tra, -trum",back:"neither",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"bd1242cf-228f-404d-8f96-a9f440842606",front:"alter, -era, -erum",back:"one, the other, second",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"6b29671b-2eb9-4240-a411-de747cd400d8",front:"uter?, -tra, -trum",back:"which (of the two)",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"88199c2c-0379-4c2f-8a02-d8f8760a0633",front:"uterque, utraque, utrumque",back:"each of the two",description:"Adjective, 1/2. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"ca57eb16-0f8e-4a09-bbcc-9b22b73c0f2b",front:"omnis, -e",back:"all, every",description:"Adjective, 3. declension",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"d0144c31-aa32-4fa0-afea-60531513117f",front:"mihi",back:"me, myself",description:"Pronoun (dat)",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"c1835d9e-6ca9-407a-a945-aebf8fe6c6c2",front:"tibi",back:"you, yourself",description:"Pronoun (dat)",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"9e0a067f-0d0c-4b80-8e73-7ce70bac4c29",front:"mēcum",back:"with me",description:"Pronoun",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"93098a1c-fdee-478a-bb63-aecaf8eff510",front:"tēcum",back:"with you",description:"Pronoun",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"e0fe8c97-1875-47e1-a5f7-ec90865ffcd3",front:"sēcum",back:"with himself/herself",description:"Pronoun",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"565add91-1061-483e-94bc-0e3995afe036",front:"prīmum",back:"first",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"18bd5b5f-3005-4556-8da5-93faaa889c94",front:"nihil, nīl",back:"nothing, not at all",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"b571709f-ea07-44d4-b28f-4cc7658ec45b",front:"quōmodo",back:"how",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"3121bd25-297d-4a0c-8d3f-0199d16fa8af",front:"hodiē",back:"today",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"0340d3cd-e5e3-4848-bb3d-797d6a2f28e7",front:"adhūc",back:"so far, till now, still",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"8771f761-6d67-495c-8f77-6d29b7f6af25",front:"deinde, dein",back:"afterward, then",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"a4447073-c1f3-48e0-bee8-ab125fc40a84",front:"praeter",back:"past, besides, except",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"1ff12b50-51b5-4279-949b-53b4bf8a2599",front:"an",back:"or",description:"Adverb",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}},{id:"fe555ee6-79f1-4d28-8301-45a4b3b9e77e",front:"valē, valēte",back:"farewell, goodbye",description:"Interjection",meta:{chapter:"XIV"}}];function Ya(e){const t=Object.prototype.toString.call(e);return e instanceof Date||typeof e=="object"&&t==="[object Date]"?new e.constructor(+e):typeof e=="number"||t==="[object Number]"||typeof e=="string"||t==="[object String]"?new Date(e):new Date(NaN)}function Qa(e,t){return e instanceof Date?new e.constructor(t):new Date(t)}function as(e,t){const n=Ya(e);return isNaN(t)?Qa(e,NaN):(n.setDate(n.getDate()+t),n)}function is(e,t){const n=+Ya(e);return Qa(e,n+t)}const rs=6e4;function hn(e,t){return is(e,t*rs)}const os=(e,t)=>{for(const n of e)t[n.id]=0},Mc=(e,t)=>{const n=new Set(t.map(c=>`${c.key}:${c.value}`));return e.filter(c=>Object.entries(c.meta).some(([a,i])=>n.has(`${a}:${i}`)))},Rc=(e,t)=>{for(const n of e.sort(()=>.5-Math.random()))if(t[n.id]<Date.now())return n},ss=e=>{const t=[];for(const n of e)t.push({key:"chapter",value:n});return t},ds=(e,t,n)=>{e==="easy"?n[t.id]=as(Date.now(),3).getTime():e==="good"?n[t.id]=hn(Date.now(),10).getTime():e==="hard"?n[t.id]=hn(Date.now(),6).getTime():e==="again"&&(n[t.id]=hn(Date.now(),1).getTime())},fs=$o("game",{state:()=>({cards:cs,quarantinedCardIds:{},cardFilters:[]}),actions:{setApp(e){this.appInstance=e},initialize(){setInterval(()=>{if(this.appInstance&&!this.currentCard){const e=Mc(this.cards,this.cardFilters);this.currentCard=Rc(e,this.quarantinedCardIds),this.currentCard&&this.appInstance.update(this.currentCard)}},500)},setFilter(...e){this.cardFilters=ss(e)},addResult(e){ds(e,this.currentCard,this.quarantinedCardIds),this.save()},load(){const e=localStorage.getItem("llpsi-vue");e?this.quarantinedCardIds=JSON.parse(e):os(this.cards,this.quarantinedCardIds),this.initialize()},save(){localStorage.setItem("llpsi-vue",JSON.stringify(this.quarantinedCardIds))}},getters:{nextCard(){const e=Mc(this.cards,this.cardFilters);return this.currentCard=Rc(e,this.quarantinedCardIds),this.currentCard}}}),ls={id:"app"},bs=$("svg",{class:"spqr",xmlns:"http://www.w3.org/2000/svg",viewBox:"0 0 94 72",fill:"currentColor"},[$("path",{d:"M71 0l2.76 2.611c2.26 3.38 5.476 6.582 9.016 8.963l-.402-.871c-.712-2.739-1.815-5.381-4.254-7.422C76.043 1.537 73.427.962 71 0zM22.215.434c-3.331 1.213-7.059 2.367-9.068 5.646-1.412 1.773-1.448 4.079-2.443 6.01 1.844-1.62 3.926-2.864 5.553-4.748 1.815-2.366 3.512-4.902 5.959-6.908zm57.844 3.676c1.32.825 2.301 2.111 2.797 3.42.99 3.021 1.466 6.207 2.885 9.039l-.088.08c-.532-.791-.802-1.758-1.627-2.455-2.467-3.025-6.763-3.816-8.355-7.406.403 2.144 1.104 4.168 2.715 5.83 2.779 2.8 6.816 4.452 8.719 7.951l.027-.029c-.711-3.302.42-6.487-.354-9.758h-.002c-.674-2.892-3.479-6.053-6.717-6.672zm-66.828.559c-1.698.406-3.206 1.368-4.396 2.752-2.742 2.689-2.462 6.83-2.076 10.457.08 1.123-.165 2.174-.086 3.223.805-1.543 2.215-2.909 3.678-4.109 3.546-2.335 7.252-5.602 7.305-9.758-1.147 2.99-4.61 4.25-6.951 6.271-1.203 1.103-2.168 2.38-2.717 3.732l-.084-.061c.288-1.196.868-2.273 1.201-3.439 1.045-3.155.83-6.95 4.127-9.068zm74.023 5.039c1.162 1.514 1.366 3.411 1.396 5.367-.531 3.611-.699 7.439-.148 11.096 0 .063-.066.109-.133.109-.318-.965-.288-2.087-.801-2.984-1.251-3.55-5.841-5.214-7.703-8.436.261 1.402.733 2.737 1.285 4.029 1.743 3.951 5.981 6.938 7.152 11.129.134.386.167.851.316 1.197a23.13 23.13 0 0 1 1.68-5.756c2.145-4.281 1.499-10.229-1.445-13.961-.518-.606-.854-1.385-1.6-1.791zm-81.117.623c-.053.013-.093.055-.143.078-2.299 2.739-3.929 5.738-3.83 9.414-.31 4.524 2.795 7.715 3.145 11.98.719-4.451 4.657-7.641 6.789-11.529.746-1.555 1.31-3.252 1.533-4.934-.301.716-.817 1.337-1.402 1.947-2.739 2.334-5.875 4.73-6.471 8.107-.1.48-.132.979-.281 1.445-.117.048-.118-.079-.168-.109l.334-4.186c.115-4.089-1.978-8.619.553-12.215-.021-.004-.041-.004-.059 0zM92.496 21.02c.749 3.814-1.089 7.002-2.561 10.16-1.035 2.195-1.371 4.669-2.037 7.021l-.203.211-.078-.074c.233-1.022.618-2.012.516-3.174.283-4.796-4.207-7.734-5.223-12.01l-.053 1.602c.383 4.187 1.568 8.058 2.918 11.873.779 1.771.541 4.071.361 5.941 1.613-2.362 3.726-4.526 5.473-6.85 2.446-4.198 3.125-10.205.887-14.701zm-91.211.637C.75 22.711.533 23.901.25 25.051c-.598 2.971-.015 6.129.863 8.855 1.067 3.42 4.661 5.862 6.477 8.992l.248.186c-.264-1.7-.4-3.53.115-5.152.782-2.596 1.681-5.133 2.283-7.809.315-2.103.863-4.434.6-6.459-.299 1.091-.646 2.148-1.248 3.098-2.476 3.503-4.941 7.66-3.234 12.135-.039.047-.094.11-.158.078-.686-1.478-.804-3.171-1.283-4.746-1.146-4.212-4.641-7.713-3.627-12.572zm82.373 11.529l-.748 1.867c-2.008 5.574-.415 12.531-3.674 17.596v.189c2.127-1.541 4.372-2.797 6.586-4.152 5.371-3.426 9.001-8.728 8.018-14.779-.38 3.625-3.325 6.302-6.221 8.914-1.866 1.868-3.113 3.953-4.709 5.914h-.201c1.182-1.681 1.916-3.546 2.029-5.65.113-3.484-1.499-6.426-1.08-9.898zm-73.393.566c.45 2.767-.73 5.209-.996 7.84-.231 2.162.12 4.294 1.08 6.082.201.562.749 1.024.885 1.572-.868-.73-1.433-1.696-2.082-2.568C6.407 42.414.486 39.692.086 34.541c-.201 2.291-.097 4.761.83 6.756 2.199 5.786 8.956 8.79 13.912 11.947-.467-1.102-1.18-2.132-1.533-3.285-1.349-5.271-.617-11.343-3.029-16.207zm70.365 8.324c-1.168 1.196-1.996 2.517-2.998 3.777-3.145 4.452-2.875 10.3-7.588 14.08 2.783-.888 5.84-1.118 8.705-1.836 5.537-1.647 11.416-6.827 12.146-12.354-.68 1.633-2.096 3.144-3.643 4.297-3.861 2.706-8.524 3.638-12.094 6.969-.384.236-.766.59-1.203.605 1.338-1.086 2.547-2.427 3.393-3.811 2.197-3.482 1.368-8.14 3.281-11.729zm-67.336.494c2.035 3.798 1.079 8.746 3.795 12.277.746 1.168 1.978 2.195 3.043 3.096l-.049.047c-.964-.42-1.859-1.023-2.713-1.73-4.64-3.56-11.561-4.044-14.324-9.891.75 4.293 4.325 8.199 8.332 10.502 3.67 2.394 8.541 2.037 12.699 3.318-3.842-2.896-4.476-7.222-6.137-11.053-1.116-2.347-2.798-4.498-4.646-6.566zm60.83 8.84c-3.344 2.133-6.022 4.918-9.033 7.625-2.044 1.726-4.537 2.441-7.105 2.986v.031l1.033.123c5.371.812 11.011 3.241 16.617 1.262 3.262-1.073 6.843-3.627 8.273-6.676-3.853 4.376-10.136 3.549-15.629 4.355-1.477.14-2.842.64-4.334.609 1.046-.47 2.326-.579 3.34-1.199 4.096-1.912 4.358-6.144 6.838-9.117zm-54.187.42c2.511 3.159 3.19 7.843 7.816 9.363.768.378 1.744.332 2.447.748-.884.127-1.647-.185-2.48-.291-5.902-1.233-13.142.34-17.572-4.373 1.682 3.08 5.13 5.551 8.473 6.535 5.141 1.631 10.527-.192 15.375-1.307.696-.17 1.545-.109 2.193-.33-2.699-.513-5.259-1.317-7.387-3.061-2.96-2.604-5.657-5.292-8.865-7.285zm32.268 10.188a17.96 17.96 0 0 0-4.207.488c-.866.727-1.755-.126-2.672-.141-5.873-1.198-10.937 1.307-15.809 3.283-3.631 1.336-8.384 1.119-11.576-.937 1.58 1.852 3.693 2.994 5.875 3.768 4.057 1.512 8.884.481 12.24-1.711 2.881-1.512 5.358-4.485 9.152-3.361-3.862 1.679-7.393 4.03-10.584 7.049l2 1.545c2.327-2.915 5.421-5.296 8.551-7.146.679-.341 1.396-.764 2.148-.855 3.845 1.757 7.28 4.764 10.381 7.889.662-.499 1.364-1.042 1.906-1.621-3.218-2.907-6.737-5.179-10.525-6.828.63-.17 1.343-.204 2.084-.191 2.042-.12 3.433 1.231 5.012 2.17 3.9 2.766 9.111 4.588 14.104 2.846 2.238-.749 4.406-2.073 5.992-3.92-3.086 2.052-7.74 2.397-11.34 1.152l-3.873-1.453c-2.584-1.283-5.729-2.027-8.859-2.023z"})],-1),us={class:"front"},ps={class:"back"},hs=$("div",{class:"ocean"},[$("div",{class:"wave"}),$("div",{class:"wave"})],-1),ms=va({__name:"App",setup(e){const t=fs();let n;t.load();const c=nt(""),a=nt(""),i=nt("");let r;const s=l=>{c.value=l.front,a.value=l.back,i.value=l.description,n&&n.play()};Kn(()=>{t.setApp({update:s}),t.setFilter("I","II","III","IV","V","VI","VII","VIII","IX","X","XI","XII","XIII","XIV"),r=t.nextCard,r&&(c.value=r.front,a.value=r.back,i.value=r.description)});const f=l=>{t.addResult(l),r=t.nextCard,r?c.value=r.front:c.value=""},b=l=>{l==="front"?r&&(a.value=r.back,i.value=r.description):n=new Audio("http://soundbible.com/mp3/Air Plane Ding-SoundBible.com-496729130.mp3")};return(l,g)=>(_t(),wn(pe,null,[$("div",ls,[bs,ge(ns,{"can-flip":!!ba(t).currentCard,onFlipped:b,onButtonClicked:f},{front:vn(()=>[$("div",us,[$("h1",null,Ot(c.value),1)])]),back:vn(()=>[$("div",ps,[$("h2",null,Ot(a.value),1),$("p",null,Ot(i.value),1)])]),_:1},8,["can-flip"])]),hs],64))}}),Is=To(),ei=So(ms);ei.use(Is);ei.mount("#app");
